[music]
Hey.
Heat. Heat. [music]
[music]
>> [music]
>> Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome back to the ask show. Today
we discuss geopolitics. We discuss
everything that's happening in the
world. It will be driven by the
questions you all ask in the super chat.
So let's get going. But before that let
us see who all is there on the live
chat. I can see HB chat DSP IPK_1s
Kotinabind Vin Hitanu Meta from Gujarat
anonymous scientist Bonswar animals from
for laugh from Mumbai. Jiram, Swami Jane
from Jaipur, Aayush Singh. Um, Shekish,
namaste. Brian, Kabona from Assam, good
to see you sir. Amand Pata from
Melbourne. Good evening. Um, yeah, good
night I suppose to you. Beneath Swami
Jan, Geopolitical Dubai from Indor,
Ainta, Anand Namaskar, Alvin Rodriguez,
hello. Hitan Shu meta once again from
Gujarat. Tjas SV, Tjas V from Kashmir.
Dave Jay Jaganat from Udisha. Kaneska
Koshik Namaskarum mastermind homo
sapiens [laughter]
uh Adita Kakare Tas Vin
Jooshi Abhishek Shukla from Kpur Laki
plays from Nepal Mlavin What's up Rachav
Nabali Tadas Namaste Anime once again
Dave Somi Jane Shrias Dave from Pune
Prardana Namaste Kanesh Kakoshik United
Challengers Animeish namaste Maya Mana
Batam from MP Rahul Himani from Mumbai
nationalist Sachi Verma namaste
umik
maar
um Suesh Pande Vishbala namaste Priyanka
Javalia good evening Sumit Agarwal Ram
sir namaste Pashant panor from Uttar
Pradesh naman Aurora hello Kishor
Chabria hello Natizen what's up Beneath
Holligo God was Suyas Pande Ajay Kumar
Akula Chetanar Sab a 17year-old from
from Laknau namaste namaste uh Adok
Shaja from Mangalore Ojasitkumar Nutan
Rosh and God was alive Bruce Wayne
Vishala once again Mana Batam Aay
Birulkar Shive
Hindul Sharma Chetan Ajay
uh Aravsha from Gujarat the Kim in the
Fourth [laughter]
uh Priyanka Javalia is a JNV math
teacher by profession. Good to see that
mathematics. I am I'm a very big fan of
mathematics as some of you may know. Uh
Manticor is a new member. Well, thank
you so much and good evening. Beneit is
joining a stream after two weeks. Well,
good to have you Beneit Nam Aurora and
everyone else. Okay, let us now get
going with some questions. Amisha Mishra
is also here. Good evening. Right, Titan
is here from Diker and everyone else.
Okay. Hey, hey, him from the north.
Right, let's take some questions. We
already have a whole lineup of questions
in the super chats. So, let's go and
take the questions. Let's see what's
question number one. Basar Kaywal, dear
sir, congratulations on crossing 300
episodes. Love and support from Moscow.
Thank you for guiding us in raising our
standards and making us better. Bharati
is hearing your voice in house. My mom
says you're part of our family. Well,
thank you so much. Thank you so much. I
really appreciate your message and
please give my my respects in in regards
to your dear mom. Thank you so much. I
really appreciate this message. That's
the most fantastic message that I could
start off the session with. So, Basar G,
thank you so much. Thank you very much.
Uh Basar Kaywal says what's the
strategic loca strategic strategic
significance of the Gilgit Baltistan
region corridor from Gilgit Gilgit
through Wakan to central Asia? How might
that benefit Bhat? Okay, for that to
understand this to take a look at this
place and understand its strategic
location, we have to look at the map. So
let's go and put the map on the screen.
Right here we are.
And here's the map. Okay, we're talking
about Gilgit Baltistan. So we're talking
about Pakistan occupied Jammu and
Kashmir.
So uh the parts of Gilgit Baltistan that
are under Pakistani occupation are
as you can see there's this place called
Gilgit and essentially it's this region
over here
and it is the part of Pakistan occupied
JNK that is attached as you can see it
has a common border with Afghanistan and
which part of Afghanistan? It's the
Wakan corridor that we're talking about.
So what's the strategic significance of
this? Well, first of all, it's the one
part of BAT that is connected to
Afghanistan. And obviously since it's
currently under Pakistani occupation, we
as of now don't have a direct access to
Afghanistan. If this border was
accessible to us, then we would not have
to deal with Pakistan to access
Afghanistan. And uh yeah, that would be
great.
Uh the second thing is that look what
you're asking is a corridor from Gilgit
through Wakan to central Asia. How might
that benefit Barat? Well to understand
whether that is this is a good idea or
not. It is not sufficient to merely look
at the map as we see it right now on the
screen that's not sufficient. We have to
look at the topography of the region. So
we have to take a look at the satellite
imagery. Now let's take a look at the
satellite imagery to understand the
topography of the region. So if you want
to create a corridor from let's say
let's go back to this map for for a
moment. Let's say you want to build a
corridor from Batwar from India into
central Asia through into central Asia
through uh Gilgit Baltistan and through
Vakhan which is uh Afghanistan.
So you would imagine that you you may
you know perhaps build a road or or a
railway or something from Shinagar
through Gilgit through Wakan into
further central Asia. That's what you
might might imagine. Now let's take a
look at the topography of the region. As
you can see, it's a frightfully mountous
region. We are talking about the
Himalayas themselves, right? So where is
Gilgit? It's here. Gilgit is here. And
as you can see, it's it's in a valley
surrounded by mountains. So it's
extremely difficult to build a road or
roads over here. If you have been to the
northern parts of India, the the Ladak
region, the Kashmir region, you will see
that the roads are you know typically
single lane roads up in the in the
mountains and it's it's really difficult
to traverse those roads and building
railways in this region is essentially
next to impossible. It would be a huge
huge undertaking to build a railway in
this region. You would have to build
hundreds of tunnels and whatnot over
here. Now here is Gilgit as you can see
if you zoom in it's just mountains and
valleys and in thin rivers. Yeah the
Hunza river you have over here. And if
we go further north into Wakan
which is here let's once again see the
map for orientation. So this region is
Vakhan. Now if you look at the
topography there's no borders visible
here and it's just mountains. If you
were to build a road through Wakhan, it
would be extremely challenging
and from Wakhan into you would have to
do it into Tajakistan. So between India,
between India and Tajakistan, you have
this small sliver of land which is
Vakhan, right? So that's the deal. So
theoretically it would be great for us
to have a corridor into Central Asia
through this region but practically it's
extremely difficult. If you want to have
a high-speed connection to Central Asia
it would be next to impossible. So
ideally what you want to do is have a
corridor into Central Asia through some
other region maybe bypassing the
Himalayas. So go from Jammu westwards,
go through uh Purushpur, go through
Jalalabad, go into Afghanistan and from
Afghanistan you go into perhaps
Turkmanistan or Usbakistan or even
Tajakistan. Tajakistan will be a little
difficult because the terrain is
challenging. So you would have to do it
that way. That's that's the right way to
do it. Go from Jammu, go westwards or go
from Amritser, go westwards through
Punjab and go into Kabul, go into
Afghanistan, Gandhar and then go
westwards into Turkmanistan or Persia or
Usbakistan you can even include
Tajakistan that is the right way to do
it from a geographic perspective from a
topograph from a topological topographic
perspective that's the way to do it. Now
the problem is that we have allowed all
these artificial borders to come up and
impede and to and to hem us in. We have
allowed foreigners the British to create
these artificial borders in our own
lands. And that's why we now because of
this artificial borders don't have
access to central Asia. So what needs to
happen is that we as a nation need to
develop the cohes fortitude to dismantle
these artificial borders. going through
Gilgit etc etc is going to be huge
challenge huge challenge it will be
better just to just fly you know
transport everything by air but ideally
you want to do it through road and rail
networks for that we have to deal with
the issue of Pakistan
okay inventing all these roundabout ways
to access Afghanistan and access central
Asia it is well it's feasible but it
will be very timeconuming very uh you
know inefficient
And it's the coward's way out in my
opinion. We have to find a solution to
Pakistan. Pakistan is the issue. Right?
That's how I see it. I may be
idealistic. I may be impractical. But
people who think impractically and make
that possible, they are the ones who
achieve real change. Right? So,
okay. Baskar Khal says how Israel a
sovereign nation lost the narrative war
in this Pakistan Gaza Hamas issue
assuming they allegedly have quite a
juicy grasp in the US tech space. Okay.
So you can you can say that Israel has
lost the narrative war in the Palestine
Gaza Hamas issue,
right? Because if you look at the
world's media, a lot of the media is is
anti-Israel
and they said the Israel has been doing
this or that or whatever, right? That's
true. A significant percentage portion
of the world's media is against Israel.
So you could justifiably perhaps say
that Israel has kind of lost the
narrative war. Boo boohoo boohoo boohoo
but
okay they lost the narrative war
assuming that is true but they have won
the actual war.
Who cares about narratives when you
achieve your actual objectives? There is
something Indians simply don't
understand.
When you win nothing,
then it's okay to try and fight a
narrative war and win a narrative war.
But when you actually achieve your
objectives, your long-term objectives,
then who cares about the goddamn
narrative war? You got what you wanted.
They have essentially finished off
Hamas. They're going to take over Gaza.
Syria is dealt with. Hisbullah is dealt
with. What else do you want? To hell
with the narratives. They want actually
what they wanted on the ground. Please
understand this my dear Indians.
What is really what is more important is
actual victory not the narrative
but the actual victory has to be a
genuine victory. So for example,
operation Sindur,
you could say that the narrative war
once again the Pakistanis because
they're supported by the western media,
they are kind of on the upper hand and
they are kind of winning the narrative
war allegedly, right? They claim that
they shot down six, seven, eight, nine,
God knows how many fighter planes and
Donald Trump supports that. That's why
you could say that Pakistanis are
winning the narrative war. But the
question is what actually happened? What
actually happened is that we destroyed
so many of their assets and we created
their their airfields and we destroyed
many of their uh we rendered many of
their airports, military airports, air
bases inoperative for a while etc. But
did we achieve any of our objectives?
What is the objective of a war with
Pakistan?
If India and Pakistan fight, are we
keeping score like a cricket match that
you I destroyed X number of planes, you
destroyed X number of planes, I got
seven, you got two, that's why I win. Is
that what we looking for?
What is the objective of war with
Pakistan? If we go to war the next time,
whenever we do, the objective is to end
the nuclear blackmail and the terrorist
blackmail.
That is the objective. Even if you take
back P but Pakistan continues as a Pak
as a terrorist nuclear armed terrorist
state, then you have really achieved
nothing.
The only objective real objective of a
war with Pakistan is to effect a regime
change and bulcanization of Pakistan. If
you don't achieve that, you've achieved
nothing.
So in case of India, operation Sindur,
you can keep claiming this that that
that that. But you we actually did not
achieve that objective. Correct?
There's no point of going to war unless
you achieve your objectives.
Oh, we we gave them a stern beating. Who
cares about your stern beating? you have
to achieve long-term objectives. So when
it comes to Israel, they have achieved
their long long-term objective. They're
on the verge of achieving their
long-term objectives. Hamas is
essentially done.
And even if Hamas tries to go back to
terrorist activities, this time Israel
is going to wipe them out of existence.
They they're going to entirely flatten
Gaza and then they take over Gaza. That
is victory. Who cares about the
narrative? So please understand the
difference between words and actions,
between narratives and actual outcomes
that you seek to achieve. Israel is one
and that's what matters. Narratives can
go to hell.
Buskar Katwal says how Thailand,
Vietnam, Malaysia, Indonesia were
allowed to retain their civilizational
identity given that they are American
vas. Have you been to Thailand?
It's very nice to go to Thailand. I have
been to Thailand once. I've been to
Bangkok. I went for the World Hindu
Congress uh late autumn uh 2023.
It's beautiful to see the way that
they've been able to preserve some of
their culture. One thing you you will
notice when you go to Thailand is nobody
gives a damn about speaking English.
There is no mental colonization like the
Indians. Indians are like, "Yes, sir. I
speak very nice English in a foreign
accent that makes me superior." The Thai
don't care. That makes the Thai people
superior to Indians. Okay. Secondly,
they still are they they they don't feel
ashamed of of flaunting their culture.
You go to Sarabumi airport, first of
all, it's named Subarabumi airport.
Imagine an Indian airport having a
Sanskrit name. No, you will name Indian
airports after random politicians.
Sometimes it will be somebody great like
Chhatravad Maharaj as in Mumbai airport.
But typically you will have some
politician after which an airport is
named. Nobody of of immense stature.
Secondly, uh if you go to Subarabumi
airport, you will see samudra mantan
there a tableau of the samudra mantan.
You will see Lord Hanuman there. Thai
version of Lord Hanuman. You will see
Thai culture which is our culture but
their culture also depicted in in a
proud way. You won't see that in India.
You go to various parts of Bangkok, you
will see statues and temples of Lord
Vishnu there and people actually go and
pray. So you will see all of that in
Thailand.
But and I am not familiar with this,
okay? I'm not being funny or whatever,
but uh there are lots of Indians who go
to Bangkok for other purposes. They
don't go for the culture, right? They go
for the red light district or whatever
the hell it is. Why does it exist in
Bangkok?
This entire prostitution business, why
does it exist? Why do all those lady
boys exist and so on? Who do they serve?
Do they serve thigh clients? No, they
serve western clients.
That's what the westerners have done to
Thailand and to a lot of the nations
they have vasalized.
Go to Japan. Go to Korea.
There is this this underbelly that
people don't talk about.
Indonesia, Malaysia, everywhere you have
something or the other. So the Americans
where whichever nations they vasalized
they've turned each of these nations
into some form of Disneyland for
themselves and that is detrimental to
the to those nations cultures. When it
comes to dharmic culture of which which
is Thai culture all of this large scale
prostitution and all of that that is not
part of our culture and yet it exists to
serve the the white man. So you see in
some ways they are retaining
civilizational identity as long as they
are pliable and they do whatever they
told otherwise there will be a student's
revolution anytime on the street on
demand. So all of that is there. So each
of these nations serves a certain
purpose for the master and as long as
they serve that purpose they are allowed
to exist in some way. That is the deal.
Muskar Katwal says, "Estimates suggest
25,000 something crores or $3 billion
worth of narcotics vessels seized by our
agencies in Bat 12 months of 2024. Is it
correct to assume that drugs are a front
for indirect funding by certain powers?
Without going into any details, yes.
Yes, drugs are a fantastic front for
indirect funding by certain powers.
That's why a drug industry exists
because drugs are are kind of a
substitute for gold. Cocaine or heroine,
I don't know what the price is, but it
is like a very stable price and the
price appreciates.
If you hold gold for 10 years, it's
going to increase in value because the
currency typically deflates. Similarly,
if you hold cocaine, heroine, whatever
narcotics, that also has has a similar
effect sadly, unfortunately. Right? Why
is there so much drug trade, drug
cartels in in South America, Central
America? They serve a certain purpose.
Why is there a drug epidemic that e
emanates out of Pakistan and and spews
over into western India? Why is that?
Why is there po cultivation in certain
foreign occupied portions of Manipur
which is connected to the golden
triangle eastwards? All of this, this
entire drug industry, drug drug business
is something that allows foreign powers
to inject cash into u into activities
and entities that serve their interests
in various countries including our
country. So that is indeed the case.
Basar Kaywal says since fifth generation
military aircraft aircraft are stealth,
what will seventh and seventh generation
have in terms of technology? Might
fighter jets be obsolete soon and UAV
the generations will start. Okay. So,
fifth generation is stealth enabled
aircraft
like the F-35, like the Sukoy 57. Uh the
the Rafal is a 4.5 generation fighter
plane with some stealthy characteristics
but not entirely stealthy.
The F-22 Raptor probably is a fifth
generation fighter plane, probably the
best in the world. Um so, you have that.
Sixth generation fighter planes will
have what? They will have AI obviously
and they will have wingmen, autonomous
wingmen. Some of those sixth generation
fighter planes and aircraft could be
entirely autonomous. Yes, AI enabled. So
I would imagine sixth generation fighter
planes will have proper stealth uh
technology as well as artificial
intelligence and wingmen aircraft which
would be like you know uh UAVs, unmanned
aerial vehicles. That is the sixth
generation. What could the seventh
generation be? I would imagine the
seventh generation aircraft will be
space. They will be able to access space
and fight from space or fight in space.
That's what I expect would be the
seventh generation, right? So you have
stealth, then you have stealth plus AI
plus, you know, networkcentric warfare
and UAVs that fight together with your
aircraft. And the seventh generation
most likely will be all of that plus
space-based warfare.
That's how I see it. I have not studied
this but yeah logically it makes sense
for me that way. Basar Kayatwal has a
lot of questions today. Baser says we
spoke about why bhat needs more nuclear
submarines and not aircraft carriers but
how exactly do nuclear submarines work
in warfare and deterrence. Okay.
So typically if you have a ship, forget
about surface ship or below surface
ship, any ship, any oceangoing vessel,
it needs propulsion, which is typically
your propeller goes around and around.
Now how does the propeller propel? Why
does it rotate? It needs something, some
source of energy, some sort of source of
fuel. Typically, it's diesel or
whatever, right? So you have a huge
gigantic ginormous diesel engine or
whatever engine that provides the power
that propels the propeller, rotates the
propeller and takes the ship forward.
And for that to work, you need a certain
amount of fuel to be stored on the
vessel. And the same goes for diesel
electric submarines. They will need
diesel fuel, which means that once the
diesel fuel is getting over, you have to
bring the submarine back to the port.
Otherwise, it will be stuck at sea
without any power. So that determines so
if it's a diesel diesel submarine the
amount of diesel the
the engine
uh the the the motor consumes
per hour or whatever it is it determines
how long the submarine's legs are mean
how far it can go. So, so if you have a
diesel engine submarine, then it
typically has a certain range after
which you have to refuel it. Either you
can refuel it at sea which will expose
it or you will have to bring it back to
port. Now, if you have a nuclear
submarine, then it doesn't have to be
refueled for several years because
that's how nuclear energy works, right?
So, that's why nuclear submarines
typically have shocking advantages over
diesel submarines or conventional
submarines. Now how do these things
work? What you have in a nuclear
submarine is a miniaturaturized nuclear
reactor.
So nuclear reactors, some nations have
those. India has has a few nuclear
reactors. There are several nuclear
reactors and nuclear reactors generally
produce electricity and they also serve
other purposes like you know generating
plutonium fuel for nuclear weapons. I
mean you can have a nuclear re reactor
that does that. But how does a nuclear
reactor work? It works by generating
heat
from file material.
The file material under goes fusion and
emanates. It emits heat and you control
the rate of the fusion reaction through
various processes through various means.
You have cadmium rods and so on that you
inject and pull out at in various ways
to control the speed of the nuclear
reaction and to control the amount of
heat heat that's emitted. If you stop
controlling that you undergo nuclear
meltdown which is what happened in
Chernobyl in Fukushima etc. So you
control that and that heat that is
produced it drives a steam turbine
like a steam engine and that that
produces electricity. That is
essentially what a nuclear reactor is.
Now you miniaturaturize that and put
inside a submarine. Then you have a
submarine that is nuclear based that has
nuclear propulsion and that's how
[clears throat] it works. Now, nuclear
submarines can stay submerged for months
as long as you have the proper equipment
on board to scrub the carbon dioxide
from the air and give oxygen back and as
long as you have sufficient food and
water on board and that can be dealt
with. You can even recycle water if you
have you know the right technology. So
as long as you can keep recycling the
air, removing the carbon dioxide, giving
out oxygen and as long as you can keep
on purifying the water and you you may
even be be able to do aro reverse
osmosis of the sea water and you know
that may also be a thing and in that
case you can have essentially a
submarine that can stay submerged for 6
months or even more potentially
depending how how what sort of crew you
have and how much food you can store on
on on board. So that is how it works. So
if a submarine can stay submerged for 6
months, incredible deterrence, right?
Imagine the deterrence it gives you.
Imagine the stealth capabilities of such
a submarine and obviously a stealth also
depends on how much noise the submarine
makes and all that. That's a whole
different story. So that's that
essentially is how nuclear submarines
work and how that's how if you have a
submarine that is on patrol for 6
months. It can be a supremely deterrent
uh entity very very stealthy. It can
stay submerged hundreds of feet below
the surface and if it it contains if if
it carries ballistic missiles, cruise
missiles then it can you know be a
extremely u valuable source of
deterrence and it'll be it could be
anywhere in the world. That's the whole
point right that's how it works. Basar
Kwal says allegedly a sir is certainly
the reason geopolitics feels like
Netflix of our generation. I'm certain
it's not just allegedly true. Thank you
sir.
>> [laughter]
>> One has to use certain terms sometimes
you know
right okay Basar says in conjunction to
the above question can can countries
like South Korea, Japan, Thailand,
Philippines etc. only be classified
truly sovereign if US military presence
for from their soil goes away entirely?
See there are when it comes to
sovereignty you have different classes
of sovereignty.
You have
military sovereignty which means that
your military is entirely controlled by
you. Second, you have territorial
sovereignty, which means you control all
your all your borders. Nobody gets to
decide who comes in, who goes out. You
get to decide that. There is territorial
sovereignty. Then you have economic
sovereignty, which means that you
control your currency and you control
your economy and nobody gets to say what
happens with your economy. That's number
three, economic sovereignty. Number four
is legislative and political
sovereignty, which means that your head
of state and your government, they're
answerable only to the people or and to
themselves. They're not answerable to
anybody else. and they decide what laws
will be passed and what laws will be
applied, what policies will will be
applied in the nation and so on. So all
of these different things they
constitute sovereignty overall. Now if
the US military presence from a certain
nation goes away, it doesn't necessarily
mean that the nation becomes sovereign.
The US may still control their economy,
the US may still control the government,
the US may still control their
politicians, the US may still control
what kind [clears throat] of policies
will be applied in the country.
So it's not enough for simply the
military presence to go away. There's a
whole lot more that that goes into all
of this. And that's why things are so
complex. I mean when it comes to many uh
EU nations, European Union nations,
there's not a single US soldier on their
soil. And yet these EU nations are not
sovereign because they don't control
their economy. They don't control their
borders. They don't control their
legislation and their policies. Right?
They have pulled sovereignty in so many
issues. which is why even if you take
away the military presence the
sovereignty isn't still there and that's
an issue. So similarly when it comes to
any other country the same applies. The
removal of a foreign military is not
enough to guarantee sovereignty. A
nation may still you know be non-s
sovereign.
They may still acknowledge someone
else's suzarentity. Basar Kayatwal says
our friend Google says US today
possesses 5,000 nuclear weapons today.
Why? What did they do with the remaining
25,000 they had in the 60s and 70s
assuming all of this is true? Well,
that's just the official figure that is
given. We don't know ex exactly what the
deal is. I mean, nobody has gone and
checked, right, how many nuclear weapons
the US has. So, the US government says
it has roughly 5,000 something nuclear
weapons. It is a figure given by the US
government. Now, they can obviously
choose to under report the numbers.
Maybe they have 70,000, but they are
saying they only have 5,000. You never
know.
You cannot take these words to be
entirely true. You should not. Right? I
can say that I am 12 years old. I can
say that I identify as a unicorn.
So will you believe me? Right? That's
how it is.
uh and certainly it's true that the two
nations the US and the USSR in the 20th
century late 20th century uh agreed to
reduce the number of nuclear weapons and
they brought allegedly the stock piles
down from very large numbers to very
reasonable numbers and I suppose there
were checks and balances in such that
both nations could kind of understand
and and and verify to some extent that
the numbers were brought down. So maybe
in the 80s it really did happen, maybe
in the 90s also, but then today you
don't have the start agreement anymore
and so on. So maybe they have 5,000,
maybe they have 25,000. And in case that
really did bring down the number from
25,000 to 5,000, what does it mean? What
happened to the remaining 25,000?
They would have been dismantled and the
file material would have been taken out
and the file material still remains
available with the US and they can build
more weapons on demand with those. They
have the designs, they have the
factories, they know how to build more
nuclear weapons. In a couple of years,
they may have 5,000 more or maybe 20,000
more. Right? So that's how it is. What
really matters is the file material,
the uranium or the plutonium. That's is
that's what really matters. And as long
as you have the technology to to to
construct certain kinds of explosive
nuclear devices, then well, you can make
as many as you want if you have the file
material. But if you don't have facile
material, then even if you have the
ability to make 30,000 nuclear weapons,
you can't because maybe you have you
only have enough file material for for a
100. So file material is what matters.
The US has a has a ton of that.
Basar Katwal says people are getting
hyped as the new Japanese PM says that
she will take care of immigrants. Right
to think nothing will happen because the
Japanese PMs are revolving doors. I
would agree with you. I am very
skeptical of of words.
Indians I mean I don't know about other
countries but Indians love words right?
If you say a few words that Indians like
my god they'll become your big fans. Um
and Indians love slogans and Indians
love headlines. Indians don't go below
that level you know surface below
surface level analysis. Most Indians I'm
sure some Indians aren't like that but
most Indians are surface level people.
Look at headlines and that's it. Aha. Oh
yeah. Oh yeah. Right. So the Japanese
media has said that she doesn't like
immigrants. She'll take care of them,
etc. Good. Fantastic. Let's see how long
she lasts. I I am extremely skeptical
that anything will happen. Whatever the
Americans want is going is what is is
what's going to happen. And the Japanese
PM can't do a thing about that.
Right. Rajendra Chula says, "How is the
US anti-India if its vasals are finding
FDA and defense deals with India?"
Right? Its vasals UK, Australia, EU,
etc. are find signing FDA and defense
deals with India. Have you seen sir the
US actions vis Pakistan?
The US is investing tremendous amounts
of money in Pakistan. The US is taking
Pakistan sides side against India. The
US is going to supply more missiles to
Pakistan. I think that that should be
enough for you to understand what the
situation is right the have you seen the
kind of tariffs they've imposed on
India? India buys less Russian oil than
China but China tariffs are way lower
than India. Now they're they're even
lower now after the recent summit
meeting between the two leaders. But
India 50% tariffs
you think they are they are pro- India
based on all of that sir you to look at
forget about what the vasals are doing.
The vasals play their own role.
So if you look at the US actions it's
clear that it's not not pro- India. It's
very pro Pakistan. It's very very it's
going very hard on India. Rajendra Chula
says if the US becomes second rate world
power who controls 7 if the US becomes
second rate world power who controls its
720 plus on an official basis and
offshore nuclear weapons can we buy it
if we become a double digit trillion
dollar economy no
if the US becomes a second rate world
power it will happen only if no long it
no longer has those 720 plus official
bases
in offshore nuclear weapons
you cannot be a first rate world power.
You cannot be a second rate power if you
still have all those things.
See what comes first is what you have to
understand. Does becoming a second rate
world power come first or does losing
all those bases etc come first. You
cannot become a second rate world power
if you still have all all those things
then you are still a first rate world
power then you are still a superpower.
So becoming a second rate world power
means that the US has already first lost
all those things.
See India today you could say is a
second rate world power. India doesn't
have any power production capabilities
comparable to the US. India is you could
say a great regional power in its region
but beyond that it's not economically
it's a very major economy but militarily
overall it's it's not in the same league
as the US, Russia and China. India so
India would you could say in the is in
the second rung of global powers. the
US, China and Russia are in the top
level. If US has to come below in to
where India is today, it will have to
first lose all those fantastic things,
right? So yeah, so it means that by the
time it all those official all those
bases will already have been lost by the
US. Can we buy it if we become a double
digit trillion dollar economy?
You don't buy military bases. You have
to bully others into giving you bases.
It's not the US did not buy these
military bases. Yeah. They [snorts] give
some money and etc etc etc. Yeah. They
have leased the bases etc. They
oops. And we're back. So the US
you see it it it it
has um you can't buy it. You have to
lease it and you can only lease it if
you are so powerful that the other
nations will fear you. You can't simply
just buy things like that. You have to
be powerful to to get that. All right.
James James is here. Look at the state
of India. Dirty roads are in horrible
condition. No infrastructure for
pedestrians. I have been to India. about
this visual guru about it. You know what
James,
you're absolutely correct. India is not
there's nothing vishwaguru about India.
The dirty roads are in a horrible
condition in so many parts of India.
Pedestrians
it's it's it's hell for pedestrians.
You are absolutely correct James.
There is nothing vishwaguru like about
India. There is so little that Indians
can feel proud or proud about. Indians
imagine that their cities are the best
in the world or whatever. That's what
they imagine because they've never been
outside.
Kabul
allegedly has better roads than many
major cities allegedly in India. The
city of Kabul.
What's the correct what's the issue? The
alleged issue is allegedly corruption.
widespread alleged corruption allegedly
everywhere all over the alleged place.
So thank you James for pointing this out
and I agree with you. There's nothing
Vishu guru like about India
really now says did you see how Takachi
behaved during the Trump visit the
Japanese on X are hailing her and
Koreans are feeling envious that they
aren't better vasals. Wow. Please
explain what benefits Japan and South
Korea got via the Apex summit.
I unfortunately did not see the videos
of how Taki behaved during the Trump
visit. I suppose Trump was Trump. He
behaved the way Trump generally behaves
and Taki I suppose would have done her
best to be a gracious host.
Um
that's all I know. What benefits Japan
and South Korea got from the Apex
summit. I am not really sure. Nobody
gets benefits. The benefit you get is
that you continue to exist and you and
nothing really bad happens to you.
That's the best benefit that you can
expect for when you're dealing with a
master like the United States.
Um so I I don't really know what
benefits Japan or South Korea have got
from the APC summit. And uh
unfortunately I've not seen the visuals
of Trump and Takachi together. I I
briefly saw something where Takachi is
standing and Trump just wandered off
somewhere. Well, Trump tends to do such
things. So, I I really don't have an
answer. I don't really know what
benefits Japan or South Korea has got
from this summit. Nothing substantial
obviously. Uh Kaneshka Koshik, thank you
very much for becoming a member. Thank
you, sir. Appreciate it very much.
Aries Manticor says, "How would a next
generation mobile submarine base improve
our naval capability? Could it support
Indian in operations in potential Sir
Creek incursion?
A submarine is not a coast guard vessel.
The Sir Creek issue is a local coast
guard level issue. Okay, let's go to the
map. Yeah, let us go to map and
understand what first of all the Cirreek
issue is briefly.
So sir creek sir creek or sir creek
whatever it's here it's between kach and
it's between the border of Gujarat Kach
and uh Pakistani occupied sind this
region here and apparently the
Pakistanis
apparently they say there's some kind of
border issue or something I'm not sure
what right so there is significant
military presence here I'm sure if we
zoom in over here we'll be able to find
something you
military activity. Now, when it comes to
any fighting that potentially could
happen here, why do you need submarines?
Why do you need a submarine for this?
There's no need for a submarine here.
This is something you can deal with with
with the air force, with some missiles
and with some soldiers.
You don't need submarines here.
Submarines are not meant for coastal
operations unless you've got a very poor
submarine capability. Submarines are
meant for blue ocean activities, cloak
and dagger activities, deterrence
activities,
um you know hunting of of naval targets
and things like that. So forget about
sir sir creek um submarines are not
relevant in sir creek. Now the question
is what would a next gen stealth mobile
how mobile submarine base?
I'm not sure if mobile submarine bases
exist anywhere in the world. What's a
mobile submarine base?
A stealth submarine base I can
understand. It's a submarine base that
nobody can see. It will have the secret
tunnels that submarines can enter
through and there will be a huge
underground cavern where you can have
like 20 submarines sitting there and
being uh refurbished or or or or or
serviced or whatever.
That's a stealth submarine base. What's
a mobile stealth submarine base? I'm not
sure what that is.
So, if we have more submarine bases and
if they are stealthy, it will certainly
improve our naval capability
significantly. But only if we have more
submarines.
If you build 20 new stealth submarine
bases, but you only have 16 submarines,
what the hell is are you going to do
with it?
What you need is more submarines first.
And as you build more submarines, you
can build more submarine bases that can
ideally be stealthy and hidden. That's
good. But first, you need more
submarines. How many submarines does
India have? 15, 16, 17, 18, something
like that, right? I'm pretty sure it's
not 20.
That is actually rather disappointing.
extremely disappointing. A nation like
India doesn't even have 20 submarines. I
don't know what the government of India
is doing. Honestly, I don't know.
Rohan Surja says your views on delusion
of Indians and have been saying
have seen many saying this if we don't
go to the US for work the US will
collapse as our education system is the
best.
Okay, look our education system is one
of the worst in the world.
Indians imagine that because they are
taught English in the education system
that's why it's one of the best. It's
because the education system makes them
believe that the education system is the
best when it's one of the worst in the
world. What's the objective of an
education system? It is to produce
extremely
confident, extremely capable, highly
skilled
young citizens who understand the world
thoroughly, who understand what it means
to succeed, what it means to fail and
how to succeed, how to not fail and they
can they should be able to start
contributing to society as soon as they
are out of the education system. But
Indians when they come out of the
education system, they're confused.
They're clueless. They have no skills.
They have no confidence.
When they join a company, they have to
be trained all over again.
It's one of the worst education systems
in the world. It's it's a system that
not only does all of this to you, it
also mentally colonizes you. It it gives
you this massive inferiority complex and
it teaches you all kinds of wrong things
about your own history, culture, and
heritage.
Right.
And uh
yeah, so that's one thing. The education
system is one of the worst. It's
garbage. The education system of India
is garbage.
Trash. Third rate. Third rate education
system. When it comes to going to the
US, if we don't go to the US, the US
will collapse. That's a joke. Yeah, it's
true. A lot lot of the US tech companies
and all, they depend on various Indian
immigrant workers and um so on and so
forth. It's not like if Indians see if
Indians were to withdraw immediately, if
you do run a thought experiment where
tomorrow morning all the Indians
disappear, then it will be a disaster
for the US. But if Indians stop going to
the US to work slowly gradually, the US
will replace these Indians with somebody
else. There'll be lots of other people
who want to go there and people who who
will come there from countries with with
better education systems. There are
plenty of Filipinos who aspire to go to
the US. plenty of well Pakistan is an
even worse education system than us
plenty of Chinese but now the Chinese
don't really want to go to the US the
the Chinese are becoming uh high income
nation in their own right now in a
pretty developed nation in their own
right and the Chinese are proud unlike
Indians the Chinese don't have an
inferiority complex they are developing
a superiority complex that Chinese are
superior even to the Americans Indians
are like yes sir you are best
uh so if Indians stop going to the US
the US will be able to find other people
to work for them. Right? So this is all
delusional thinking and it's it's it's
because of the education system that
imparts that imparts this delusions to
Indians. Okay. Next
nationalist says AI funding bubble your
thoughts should how should India act?
Look AI fund AI is is here to stay first
of all and the there may be kind of a
bubble right now to some extent. uh
maybe there is too much being invested
into AI companies and most of these AI
companies could go bust eventually and
the bubble may burst but AI is a
transformative technology that is here
to stay and it's going to transform
human history
that is for sure so what should India do
India should pursue AI determinantly
India should be very determined very
very clear about India becoming a major
player and a leader in the AI space
India cannot afford to get left behind
like it is currently completely left
behind in the area of space space
exploration. India is left behind now.
So we can't allow that to happen in AI
but India is right now not even a player
in AI. So what should India do? India
should do whatever it takes to become a
major player and one of the leaders in
AI technology and for that it it is not
enough for the government to act and to
to coin some slogans and give maybe $10
million to some kind of scheme
somewhere. H the Americans are investing
hundreds of billions of dollars. The
Chinese are also doing that. Whatever
the Americans do, the Chinese are trying
to emulate and and exceed.
And in India, what are we doing? Ladly,
behas and all that. India should act
otherwise we're going to be left behind
and we will essentially be colonized all
over again.
Rywick says Bangladesh is now East
Pakistan. Yes, indeed. Tourism is
increasingly is increasingly
tourism is increasing exponentially in
the northeast mainly Megallay. Should we
be alert of any terrorist attack at
Dawoki Umangot border because it's a
high tourist place. Okay. I I don't know
what this is Dawokiangot border. I've
not been there. Uh if tourism is
expanding in the far east of India
that's fantastic. There was a time when
tourism was booming in Manipur until
2023 early 2023.
There was a time when business was
booming in Manipur. Everything is
crashed now. So you already see a
disaster there. Now as we know as you
rightly say Ritwick, Bangladesh is now
East Pakistan all over again. And
Megallaya is a state of bat which
borders
uh Bangladesh East Pakistan. Let's go to
the map.
So we are talking about Megallaya.
Here we have Megallay which is north of
uh East Pakistan.
And what border is it? Daoki Umangot
border. Let me see if I can find it over
here. Diangot border.
I'm not sure if I can locate that.
Diangot. Let's see.
Umangot.
Okay, this is the place.
Um,
so there's a border here
and
it's a high tourist place for some
region for some reason along the border
with East Pakistan. Why would you need a
high tourism place? Maybe there there
are some there are some attractions
perhaps over here. I don't know. There's
a night camping thing and all and the
border is right right over here. So
yeah, I suppose that the government of
India will have to well be on high alert
because yes, Bangladesh is now back to
being East Pakistan.
Uh I hope that no such untoward incident
happens and so on. But we have to be
careful.
No question about it. So I agree with
you. We should be very alert. They
should be on high alert for any kind of
uh
you know for any kind of such action
that could could come out of Bangladesh
for sure very important
really now says it's also a shame that
many of the 8,000 plus meter peaks like
K2 are in Gilgat Paltistan and now
Pakistan exploits the hills and allows a
lot of hunting of rare fauna.
Pakistan will do that, right? Pakistan
is up for sale as we know. What what is
the difference between India and
Pakistan? Both are nations with
allegedly high corruption and blah blah
blah. But India is it focuses on
infrastructure. It to a large extent
does care about its citizens way more
than the Pakistanis do. And India is not
up for sale, not blatantly up for sale.
So Pakistan will will exploit
everything. They will allow hunting of
rare fauna. They will allow exploitation
of mineral resources, mining of mineral
resources. They will allow whatever
whatever outsiders want whatever a more
powerful richer country wants they will
allow them to do whatever they want as
long as the Pakistani generals their
pockets are being lined. So it's a very
unfortunate obviously peaks like K2
which are Indian peaks are currently
occupied by Pakistan. Gilgad Pakistan
isn't currently much of it is currently
occupied by Pakistan. Yeah. So that's
the case. So if you want this to end
then we have to take some action in that
direction.
UMX says, "I study in a so-called top
college where a 60-year-old professor
worships Churchill, ignores actual
learning and pushes his own glorified
glorified book instead." You see, this
is India and this is the Indian
education system which is utter garbage.
A 60-year-old professor worships
Churchill,
the man who
who engineered a genocide
in Bengal.
That man Churchill who said that Indians
are a beastly people with a beastly
religion
right that is Churchill and and these
idiots these imbeciles
these imbeilic professors they they
worship people like Churchill. So many
of these professors are are are super
mentally colonized. They are they they
they hate their own country. They
consider their own country to be
backward and that and they try to impart
that that brainwashing onto f onto new
generations and they succeed to a large
extent. someone like UMX is is a rarity
because I I'm pretty sure many of his or
her co- students will be very impressed
with this professor right and these
professors are typically have some third
rate book that they have written and and
they they teach you from that I I have
been through that also personally some
third rate book written by some third
rate Indian professor that becomes the
standard book through which you're
supposed to study and if you try to
study from that you will learn nothing
you will end up more confused than ever.
So that's the deal with the Indian
education system and apparently we are
in this new education policy thing and
that is the best thing in the world
which is a non which is a joke. It's
nonsense. The new education policy is is
is nothing but like it's like attempting
to to to to put a bandage a band-aid on
a gunshot wound, right? It doesn't solve
any of the real issues. It just tries to
cover everything up. Sad.
Aris Manticor says, "If Pakistan and
Bangladesh cross our red lines to such a
deep extent, would we be forced to
change the geography to end the problem?
Should we do it in a hyper blitz way
that others can only watch it happen?"
Look,
Pakistan and Bangladesh are entirely
different entities. Bangladesh is no
match for India. If Bangladesh tries to
cross a red line, Bangladesh will be
obliterated.
Its geography will change.
And Bangladesh simply can't stand up to
India if a war happens.
They can say whatever they want on
social media. You know we people in the
subcontinent, we love slogans. We love
boasting. Right? So the Bangladeshes are
just like us. They do the same thing.
We'll do this, we'll do that, we'll take
the seven sisters, blah blah blah. They
they boasting on top of that, you know,
from the rooftops.
But if something actually happens,
they're going to scurry. they're going
to run. So Bangladesh, forget about
Bangladesh. If if they try something
funny, they're going to pay a very bad
price for it. Very very high price for
it. When it comes to Pakistan, if the
Pakistanis cross any of our red lines,
will we have to deal with them? Now the
question is what do we do and how do we
deal with them? Do we again slap them on
the wrist and make some of their air
bases inoperative for 6 months? Is that
enough?
Will that change Pakistan's behavior? We
did operation indur. We took out a bunch
of terrorists. Sure. In those drone
strikes.
Then there was an escalation and we to
we uh rendered many of their uh air
bases, military air bases inoperative.
We hit about 11 air bases in about 20
minutes or something. Right? We did all
of that. We took out their AVAC
aircraft. We took out many of the
Chinese issued radars and much more. But
what's the outcome of that? Pakistan is
still there. Their objectives haven't
changed. Their behavior hasn't changed.
They now have a very strong backing from
the US. What did we achieve? We achieved
nothing actually.
We did not achieve any long long-term
beneficial objectives for us. So my
point is if we go to war the next time,
we need to be very clear about what we
are trying to achieve. Are we trying to
teach them a lesson? Are we trying to uh
have a scorecard like a sports match?
like a football match 3052 whatever. Is
that what we want? What's the point of
doing all that?
You will kill let's say 200 terrorists.
They'll bring 3,000 more in 6 months.
What's the point of all this? If you're
going to have a war with Pakistan, it
should end in a decisive victory. There
should be a regime change and
bulcanization. Otherwise, why are you
going to war? What is this? Some kind of
sports match that you're seeing live on
hot star or something? Gioar, what
whatever that is. Is that the objective
of warfare?
we have to be a little more serious
about what we do
right and since we have decided that we
are no longer going to worry about the
Pakistani nuclear blackmail then let's
do something about it so if we go to war
the next time it can't be something that
lasts 7 weeks it can't be something that
we slowly escalate over 3 days like we
did in operation sindur first day we had
certain rules of engagement and the uh
air force was not allowed to do certain
things and so apparently allegedly
that's what some military personnel are
saying
we can't have that we have to give the
armed forces a clear objective
regime change bulcanization and we have
to tell them make it happen as far as
fast as possible ideally 72 hours so
that for that you need a hyper blitz
blitzkrieg
right
fast snail I love that name [laughter]
fast snail yes should political science
be a mainstream course alongside STEM
just like the US. Maybe that will help
more deserving people in to be in
governance and policy.
Well, first of all, the ter the the the
name the term political science is I
don't agree with it because if you know
what actual science is, then you will
know that political science isn't
science. It's the study of of state
craft.
So I I would say it should be called
state craft,
not political science. First of all,
that's a minor disagreement I have. I I
despise the term political science and
social science, those two terms, because
th they are so wrong. There's nothing
scientific about these things. So, I
would call it statecraft. Could
statecraft be a mainstream course
alongside STEM? Well, it depends. It
should be offered as a mainstream course
to those who seek to understand the
subject. Uh, it should be offered as an
optional
mainstream course.
And those who want to to to take it
full-time, well, it should be definitely
available for them. Um, and there are
people who want to,
you know, be in governance, be in
policy. They also for that they you need
to understand science, technology,
engineering, all of that. So yeah it it
does make sense to
to offer something like political
science or state state craft state craft
as a mainstream course. I suppose in
Indian universities you have master's
degrees and whatn not in political
science right I'm not sure what the
syllabus is like and what the study I've
known students when I was a student
myself who was studying political
science I had no idea what they were
studying but okay political science
fantastic good for you that's how it was
so my question is today if you have
master's degrees that are being offered
in political science what exactly are
the teaching I have not seen the
syllabus I hope the syllabus is good and
what they're teaching is something that
is genuinely of some use because uh look
In India, they teach everything like
they teach philosophy. It's all
theoretical. There's no application that
is taught.
Ideally, you should teach everything in
a way that you can apply in real life.
So, if if that can be done, I would be
very much in favor of that. Yeah, I
would have loved to study state craft
alongside alongside STEM. Uh that would
have been great.
Kan Mor says, I have come up with a few
scenarios that might be that might
change
our education system. Number one,
military rule. Number two, single party
winning elections in all states. Number
three, freedom of temples in
establishments of Google. Number four,
pray to God. Any other scenario? Well,
sir, I'll tell you what. If you have
military rule,
you won't have elections.
Okay? If you have military rule, then
why do you need elections? You decide
who be who who rules each party.
If you have military rule then the
military dictatorship will decide. We'll
appoint people to rule each state. Why
do you need elections for that?
Right? So that's one. Freedom of
temples, establishment of gurugs. Sure.
Freedom of temples very much important.
Yes. Pray to God. Well, you can't force
people to pray to God.
Let people decide.
Give them the right education. An
education that is grounded in your
culture and your cultural values and
your heritage. In that case more people
will be aligned with your culture and
civilization. That's what you can't
force people to pray to god.
And even in in historically in our
civilization there have been people who
have been agnostics and atheists. What
is charvak philosophy? It's atheism
isn't it? That was still part of dharma.
So you can't force people to pray to god
but you can give them the right
education. Um so how does military rule
change our education? It can because it
can do things that otherwise you know a
democratically elected government can't
because we have this democratically
elected government for the past 11 years
that has changed nothing of any genuine
consequence in the education system. So
yeah, you would certainly need a more
powerful government at the center
without which education reform is next
to impossible. You would need the kind
of government at the center that has the
same kind of powers that the Chinese
Communist Party has. In that case the
education system can be significantly
reformed.
Um so my
single criterion
is it's not military rule. It is an all
powerful central government with the
same kind of powers that the Chinese
Communist Party has. But it should not
be a communist government. It should be
government that is inclined that is
aligned with India's civilization and
civilizational heritage. the dharmic
government that's what you would need in
that case everything else flows from
that
kartikishi says the US wants to finish
Hinduism and India both China wants to
finish India only is this statement
right what exactly does China want from
India let's ask ourselves what does
China seek let's set the US aside for a
moment let's think about China what does
China seek the Chinese obviously
see India as the only nation that can
challenge them in in Asia in Eurasia
there's another beast called Russia
which is an issue for China but if you
look at only Asia
exclude the Europe part then it's India
of course much of Russia is in Asia but
let's talk about the nonRussian part of
Asia then yeah there's India and the
Chinese what do they want from India
they would see in an ideal world
for China you would not have India you
would have different kingdoms in India
or different states.
That's the ideal situation for China. So
they want ideally India to be bulcanized
and then they will deal with each local
government, each local government
individually. That's the what that's
what they want. They they don't care
about Indian culture. They don't love
it. They don't hate it. They couldn't
care less whether it lives or dies. If
it lives and thrives, they're okay with
it. They have they have nothing against
India's culture and civilization
right that is the one thing they
actually respect about India that we
once were a great civilization
and today why do they mock India because
we are no longer aligned with our own
civilization we are slaves of the west
that's why they express contempt towards
India and towards Indians you see they
don't respect India for this reason
because we have moved away from our own
civilization we are now slaves of the
So, so you're right. The Chinese don't
want to finish Hinduism. They couldn't
care less. They only want India to be
balconized. When it [clears throat]
comes to the US, they also want India to
be balconized. But that's not enough.
They want India to be Christianized
also.
That's the difference.
Ankit Koshel says, "Appreciate your
position on Buddhism, Hinduism." Attisha
says said that the only three persons in
India
Atisha said that only three persons in
India who can differentiate between
Buddhism and Hinduism.
There's plenty of differences between
mainstream uh Hindu dharma and both the
dharma. Plenty of small differences.
Let me give you some examples. H
if you see various
paintings or or or or
mortis of Buddhist deities,
you will see that they are standing on
some other figures, right? Let's let's
take a look at this.
Let's go to uh Google. One second. Uh
let's put that on the screen. Here we
are. Here we are. So let's say
Aalokeshwara.
Uh let's us see a depiction of
Aalokiteshwara.
Okay. Alokitwara is just seated.
Okay. Let's see Vajraani. Let's see
Vajarani.
Vajraani.
This is a Buddhist deity.
And you will often see
um vajraani
you will often see that these deities
are depicted as trampling over Hindu
gods. [snorts]
Okay. Who do we else have Buddhist
deities?
Buddhist deities.
So let us see
Padma Samhava. What do we have?
Trampling over Hindu gods. Let's see
this
trampling. Let's see.
So which gods is this? Trampled gods and
deities. That's very interesting, isn't
it?
So for example, over here this uh this
Buddhist deity is trampling over Lord
Shiva. as you can see. So you will not
see any Hindu deities behaving in a
disrespectful fashion towards deities of
of uh other dharmic uh path. Right?
Trampled figures underfoot.
Who is this here? Not sure.
So you will see this very often in in
Buddhist imagery that Buddhist deities
are are trampling on Hindu gods.
[snorts]
So that is one difference between
Buddhism and Hinduism. Then you have
other issues also like you know other
other factors also between Buddhism and
Hinduism that are different. So you can
for example the way the atma is regarded
the soul in mainstream Hindu dharma
uh the soul is permanent.
Right? In both the dharma the soul is
not permanent. The soul itself is is
something that can be destroyed.
But then why are you taking
reincarnation after reincarnation? If
the soul itself is not permanent, then
who is being reincarnated
and why are you doing all this? So
that's another question in Buddhism that
is different from Hinduism and so on. So
you can certainly find all kinds of
nuances and small differences here and
there, but overall
overall
the morality is very similar.
For example, you can find similar lots
of differences different kind of
differences between between let's what
we call Hinduism and Janism. We can even
find significant differences between
Shvite Hinduism and Vishnava Hinduism.
So why isn't Shvite Hinduism different
separate religion and Vishnav Hinduism
the separate religion? In the future
they may even ask for that that let's
make shite shaism different a different
religion and vishnavism a different
religion and everything a different
religion because there are so many
differences.
So you know
our our our our
civilization has a very ancient history.
It's rich complex and super diverse and
you can find all kinds of nuances and
differences.
Prattana says once may need a white wife
to be a pus. Erica Kirk of all of a
sudden seems sees similarities between
her husband and JD with her husband in
JD and that kind of hug is not normal in
the US or anywhere in the world. By the
way, that kind of hug is not normal
anywhere in the world. I will not go
into the details of the hug because
there's no point.
Um for if you want to know what I'm
talking about, let's Google it. Uh
JD Vance Erica
Kirk hug.
Let us see what this hug was like.
So this is the hug we're talking about.
And uh that is definitely not normal,
inappropriate behavior. I would say
that's not um I don't think it's normal
behavior in any any kind of society but
whatever. So the point is that u JD
Vance his constituency is the is the
MAGA crowd the white rednecks the white
uh supremacists the the Christian
supremacists
that crowd that's the Republican base
isn't it and um what it so happens that
JD Vance's wife is of Indian origin and
she's a practicing Hindu now he claims
that she's an agnostic she's not really
a practicing Hindu she's agn she's kind
of agnostic
in In the past she was a practicing
devout Hindu according to himself but
now he's changed his tune she is now an
agnostic person and he hopes that she
comes around to accepting his flavor of
Christianity whatever it may be right
but even if Usha converts to
Christianity caves in gives in and
converts to Christianity will that be
enough for the
Republican voters the problem is she
will never be white
right no matter how much she tries to
become more and more American, convert
to Christianity, uh, get baptized, go to
church 78 times a week or whatever the
hell it is, she'll not be white, she'll
not be good enough, right, for the
racists. So JD Vance, if he wants to be
the president of the US in the future,
maybe run for Porus in 2028 or whenever
it is, then he may find Usha to be a
liability.
So what do you do about it? Well, if
you're American, it's easy. You get
divorced. The Americans, well, for them,
divorce is a way of life, isn't it? Not
like not like Indians where divorce is
still a rarity
and and matrimon alliance, husband,
wife, that thing. It's it's essentially
for life. That's how it's supposed to
be. [clears throat]
So, what could JD Vance do? Well, it's
it's possible that he may divorce Usha.
And it looks like from that hug that we
saw, there may be a match that has
already been made for him with Eric
Khak, the the with the widow of that
fellow, Charlie Kirk, who was shot about
a couple of months ago. Just a couple of
months down the line, she's already
angling for a new guy. And if he does
marry her, then he's going to be like
the best candidate the the MAGA crowd
can ask for because he is a Christian
who divorced his wife because she's not
Christian. that that makes him a hero
and he marries a deeply devout
apparently Christian woman Erica Kirk.
So that will be a match made in heaven
and a political match made in he heaven
for him. So I think that that is a
scenario that may actually unfold.
Ankur white says India's digital
sovereignty sold to open AI and AWS
already.
If you say so. Is it true?
Open AAI,
Amazon Web Services, there also Google.
Um I hope the government is
taking the right calls on these matters
because when it comes to all the
different kinds of sovereignty, one of
the weakest points for India is digital
sovereignty.
I would not consider India to be
digitally sovereign or technologically
sovereign nation.
Anonymous scientist says forecast for
India Pakistan issue. Will India punish
Pakistan without any provocation? Longer
we wait the more difficult it will
become for India.
forecast.
I think India it will be I hope I am
completely wrong about this but I think
India will not punish Pakistan without
Pakistan
doing some kind of provocation.
I hope I'm completely wrong because like
you say the longer we wait the more
difficult it will become for India
because the Americans the Saudis etc
will will bolster Pakistan with arms
ammunition weapon systems funds whatever
right so the longer India waits the
stronger Pakistan will become it's the
stronger Pakistan's position will become
but if India punishes Pakistan without
provocation then India will be demonized
India will be taken to to to the United
Nations the UN will force a change issue
a resolution condemning India maybe the
Americans will will impose sanctions on
India. So you see if we punish Pakistan
without provocation
then India could be hurt very badly by
the Americans. The Americans may be
waiting for India to do this. And the
problem is that even if you punish
Pakistan after a provocation the
Americans will still try their best to
stop India.
So that's where we are. We are caught
between a between the devil and the deep
sea kind of between a rock and a hard
place. And the government of India has
to do what's right for the longerterm
national interest of India, not the
short-term interest. Maybe we have to
swallow some short-term pain.
What's my forecast? My forecast is that
India will not do anything without
provocation. I hope I'm completely wrong
about this.
Pratana says, "Will the US nuke the
world if it gets nuked by Russia?" The
US will nuke every single major country
in the world, not just once, but
completely flat out if it gets nuked by
anybody.
So
not by anybody,
by Russia or China.
If the US finds itself in a position
where it is on the verge of losing a
nuclear exchange, it will launch an
all-out nuclear attack on all the major
countries of the world. The the logic is
that if I go down, the whole world goes
down. Nothing survives. So yes, they
will do that.
Critical critical says, did the US
really train ravens to drop bugs and
dolphins for spy missions?
during cold war. Could gene editing and
modern technology look make animal spies
useful again? Let's take the first half
of the question which is a separate
question. Did the US really train ravens
to drop bugs and dolphins for spy
missions during the cold war? I am
trying to figure out how can a raven
which is a crow a crow is roughly this
size depending if it's a mountain crow
it's a large crow. If it's a regular
crow, it's a smaller crow. A raven is a
is a crow like bird. If you for the
uninitiated, it's it's just a crow. So
I'm wondering how can a raven
drop a dolphin? A dolphin is well the
standard issue dolphin is larger than
than a human being. How can a raven drop
a dolphin?
My point is please phrase your questions
properly.
Okay. [laughter]
I know that's but not what you asked.
You asking whether the Americans trained
ravens and dolphins to do various kinds
of things. Yeah, I'm sure they did.
Dolphins for sure. Ravens, I'm not
really sure, but it's why not? Ravens
are pretty intelligent creatures. Ravens
are among the ravens and crows, all the
corvids, they are among the smartest,
the most intelligent birds around. So if
you want if you want to to to to train
birds to do various things, I would say
the crows and the ravens and the corvett
are at the top of the list. So I'm
pretty sure they must have done that.
And dolphins for sure they even trained
dolphins and whales to to deliver
explosive devices on suicide missions
and the dolphins and whales obviously
wouldn't know what what's going to
happen to them. Yeah, they did that.
Could gene editing in modern technology
make animal spies useful again? They
could very much do that. it they could
even have all kinds of effects on human
beings also. Yes, very much so.
Rene Kumar says looking at the intents
of countries what's the future cold war
is the future a bipolarization of the
world there's not going to be a
multipolar world order there is not
going to be a multipolar world order
it's going to be a bipolar world order
now what kind of bipolar on one side
you're going to have the US and all its
vas on the other side what do you have
do you have China and vas like Russia
and India or do you have ra even if you
have ra who dominates it obviously China
will dominate it so it looks like that's
the that's the future I hope that's not
the case I hope there's a tripolar world
order with India somehow as a poll but
it's very unlikely given the direction
that India is taking not becoming a
technologically sovereign nation not
becoming a leader in AI not becoming a
leader in the space race not uh
revamping the education system not
dealing with the alleged corruption
India will remain mediocre this way so
the future is a bipolar world order most
likely with the US and China as the two
poles and everybody else vasals
buai says there were more than 100
million Germans in Eastern Europe today
in its It's less than 1 million today.
What happened to them?
We do not speak about it. It is not
supposed to be spoken about. What
happened to all those Germans? 10
million Germans. Today it's less than 1
million. Where did the 9 plus million
Germans go? No, we don't talk about it
because that's after the Second World
War. That's when the Allies had won. The
Allies were the good guys. The Germans
were the bad guys. So in case 10
million, 9 million Germans disappeared,
they were bad guys. We don't talk about
it.
It was a genocide.
Aramal Biju says, "What is the end goal
of people behind power? Why create
instability in small and emerging
economies? Are there any powers
resisting them?" What's the end goal of
people behind power?
To understand that to understand that we
have to first ask ourselves what is
power?
What is power?
Power means is it control? Is it money?
What is it?
So then a better way to ask ask this
question is what's the difference
between influence and power. Influence
and power are not the same thing.
They're very different. Maybe I am to
some extent influential. Me I have what
is it 949K subscribers on YouTube and I
have what 200 something thousand on
Twitter and so on. So overall if you add
it up maybe maybe close to a million. So
me so what it means let's say I have a
million followers across the spectrum h
subscribers followers what whatever you
want to say what does it mean it means
that when I speak some of them will pay
attention sometimes
yeah some of them subscribe to me
because they think that I have something
important to say some of them subscribe
to me because they perhaps like me for
some reason some of them subscribe
because maybe I'm funny for them maybe
I'm entertaining whatever so it means
that if I so I have the influence over
some kind of influence over 1 million It
means they will listen to me sometimes.
That's influence.
What's power?
Let's say I have 1 million slaves,
highly armed, highly trained slaves who
will unquestioningly obey my every
command.
Does that not make me a totally
different beast from a guy with a with a
1 million subscribers?
1 million strong army who will do
whatever I say.
That is power. That is how do I get
that?
So why do I have the power? Because they
will do exactly what I say without
question, without hesitation.
So I have complete control over them.
Power is control.
So if you want to do something alone,
it's very hard. But if you have a
million people doing everything for you,
you can do you can make miracles happen.
You can shape the world in your image,
you can create the kind of world you
want.
That is power.
It's addictive, I suppose, right? So
some people desire it. So the end goal
of people behind power is to control the
whole world to have more and more and
more power.
That's essentially the end goal. People
who who want power, the people who
desire power, the people who have power
and they want more, they essentially
want to control the whole world. And to
do that they will to achieve that they
will try and do anything. Create
instability, create wars, create strife,
create create mayhem unless they are
good people who want to use power for
good reasons. In that case it may not be
the case.
Teen Talks Dharma says love you sir. I'm
growing long hairless just like you
will. Thank you so much. Thank you very
much. I really appreciate that and all
the best for your hair growth journey.
Okay, Bishuai says I think choke points
harmed Russia and the USSR a lot and
India has been lucky that we don't have
that problem. I completely agree with
you. So what choke points is Bijai
speaking about? Let me show you.
Let's go to the map and let's understand
what choke points we are discussing over
here. So when it comes to Russia, let's
go to the far east of Russia, which used
to be the far east of the USSR.
So see if you go to the north, okay,
if you go to the northern parts of
Russia, you will see, okay, this this
photo was clearly taken in the summer.
If you zoom out, you will find that
these places are all at very high high
latitudes and typically the oceans are
frozen over here in winter. So you can't
really have naval bases this high north.
You need to have naval bases where the
water is liquid and not frozen year
round. Even if you go to a place like
Vladivito,
okay, Vladivito, even at the port of
Vladivito, several months of the year
the sea is frozen.
So Vladivosto in this region you have a
major Russian and formerly Soviet naval
base because no further north there's no
point having one. So they have a naval
base here and to take your ships or
aircraft carriers, so submarines out
into the open sea, you have to either go
past this choke point here, this narrow
passage where the Russians, sorry, where
the Japanese can keep an eye on what
you're doing and Japan is occupied by
America, so the Americans will do that.
Or you can go through maybe here, which
again is through Japan, and the Japanese
will know exactly what you're doing. Or
you can go through here once again over
here. The Japanese and even the Koreans,
South Koreans who are again under US
occupation will keep an eye on what
you're doing. So it's almost impossible
for Russian activity to not be
monitored. It's impossible for them to
keep it secret, keep it stealthy.
Massive problem with this choke point
further north. It's impossible to have a
major naval base because of the freezing
problem. If you go westwards,
okay, so if you go westwards, you have
St. Petersburg, major naval place. Once
again, if you want to go out into the
open sea, you have to go through all
these choke points where you where
everybody will keep an eye on you. If
you want to go north from the Baron Sea
into the Norwegian Sea and so on, then
once again, you have to pass through
places where the Americans and the West
can keep an eye on you. Um, if you are
in the Black Sea, the Russians have a
Black Sea fleet. The USSR also had the
Black Sea fleet. If they wanted to go
into the Mediterranean, they had to pass
through two critical choke points,
right? the straight
of Bosphorus
over here
and also
uh the other one after crossing the sea
of Marmma the straight of Galipoli
uh the D the Darden straight and once
again you have to pass through the Asian
sea the Ionian sea where you have all
these Greek islands that are controlled
by the US so you see the the Russians
and the Soviets were completely choked
off they were cut off through these
island chains and that was a huge
detriment for them. When it comes to
India, we have no problem. We dominate
the Indian Ocean region but we are a
nation without any ambition whatsoever.
At least our leaders don't seem to have
any major naval ambition which is why
India is a second great world power
today.
See we are lucky we don't have the
problem but we are not lucky in in terms
of the kind of leaders we have had in
the past.
Anonymous scientist says why MAGA
supporters hate Indians so much.
Pakistanis, Bangladesh and other ethnic
ethnicities don't get similar hate. It's
because Indians are mainly Hindus,
polytheists. The Pakistanis,
Bangladeshes, etc. They are Muslims and
Abrahamic religion which doesn't get
that kind of hate because they are
people of the book.
It's simply to do with Hinduism and
Hindu phobia. That's all. And when it
comes to other ethnicities like the
Japanese, the Koreans who used to the
Koreans used to be Buddhists, now they
are mainly atheists or Christians, well
that's good. And the Japanese are still
mainly polytheists. Those of them who
are not atheists, but the Japanese are
under US occupation, so they are good.
They're good boys.
That's how it goes.
Ankit Gupta says, why do nations to have
Japan, Nihon, Iran, Persia, Germany,
Deutseland, son, Sri Lanka, etc.? Is it
just names or what's the origin of this
India Bharat? When it comes to Japan and
Nihon or Nepon, Japan is a name given by
foreigners.
What is India? It's a name given by
foreigners, right? We are like India,
India in a cricket match should be bat
bat. But no, we are India India. We have
become mentally coronized. So India is a
name given by foreigners. Our actual
name is Bharat.
Similarly, when it comes to Japan, it
used to be Nihon or Nepon. But Japan is
a name given by foreigners. When it
comes to Iran, well, that's a name that
has been recently used for the country
Iran Shahar. Historically, it was
Persia.
That's why we called the people who came
from Persia Paresis from the land of
Paris.
Uh so that's a deal with Iran. Germany
is a word. It's a name given by
foreigners. The actual name of the
nation is Deutscheland. Tlan son is a
name given by foreigners. The actual
name of the island is Lanka or Sri
Lanka. That's how it is. So if you have
two names, one is a name that's given by
foreigners. And that's China. I'm Jeang
Wo. Do you know that the real name of
China is Jong Wo? It's not China.
China. China. China. China. That's a
name given by foreigners. So that's the
deal. It's typically your own name and a
name that foreigners use for you. That's
how it is. [sighs]
Anonymous scientist says, "Which country
will soon feel the wrath of Uncle Sam?
Nigeria or Venezuela? Any forecast?" I
think both could very rapidly face the
wrath of of Uncle Sam. See, these are
both helpless nations. These are not
nations that can mount any challenge to
a US occupation, invasion, whatever to
US attack. They could both feel the
wrath of Uncle Sams soon. Venezuela
maybe it has slightly more advantages
than than Nigeria. Nigeria is a nation
in Africa that's a very poor third world
country. They have no defenses, nothing.
If Uncle Sam decides to walk in this,
Uncle Sam just walks in. There's nothing
Nigeria can do about it. Nigeria won't
dare to take any kind of action.
Venezuela will try to defend itself. So,
I would say that Venezuela is a little
harder nut to crack for the US compared
to Nigeria. But Nigeria is further away.
Um, so what could happen first?
What could happen first?
I don't know. I can't say which is
first. I in my opinion both could soon
face the wrath of Angula unless Nigeria
takes some actions against Boo Haram
because Boo Haram has been running
rampant in Nigeria and
perpetrating all kinds of atrocities
allegedly against Christians for a very
long time and that's why Trump is
unhappy. Right? So Christians obviously
are the first citizens of the world
today. So if that doesn't end soon then
maybe maybe Trump will take some action.
Venezuela it's a different different
case. I can't say which will be first.
Anakulkarni says thought on OG Cholukia
are the are they and Solen is related.
See today we're discussing geopolitics.
We'll not discuss history in detail.
Maybe I took one or two history
questions by mistake. Chalukia
there is the there is the Soleni dynasty
in western India. There's the Chaloki
dynasty in southern India. Are they
related? Most likely they have some some
kind of relationship. Yeah. So the
Solinkas Solenis are called Chowukas
today for some reason.
uh maybe there's some reason good reason
behind it but as far as I
regard them I regard them as Solankis
not as challas maybe there is some
relationship okay Pratt Dana says how do
we have AI based defense system by the
US AI is being used in technology behind
the scenes question mark missile
accuracy also so show showed some AI in
action
[clears throat]
Um
is AI being used in Indian Indian um
weapons?
It's possible some form of AI is being
used. You don't need very advanced AI.
See the kind of AI that people are used
to these days, the the consumers are
used to is your uh generative AI, the
chat GPD kind of things, right? you ask
a question and it it generates
a response based on probabilistic
statistic probabilistic whatever thing
right
um that's the kind of AI that we are
accustomed to as customers consumers but
in military AI it's a whole different
beast uh
and it doesn't have to be that advanced
so all you need see for example um the
missile defense system the the air
defense system that we have uh that was
operational that was u that was seen in
operation during operation Synindur
which brought down all those Pakistani
drules all those Pakistani missiles etc.
I am sure that the targeting was not
done by human beings. The targeting was
done by computers. So those computers
they are not really artificially
intelligent computers. They
[clears throat] have tracking tracking
mechanisms.
They typically will have radars that can
track multiple targets at once. Right?
And you can network all the guns that
are part that have the to a bunch of
radars. So each gun knows
how many objects are intruding into your
airspace and then there may be a
collective computer that directs each
gun individually so that you are not
wasting your your ammunition on the
single target. So that's not really AI.
It's it'sworked.
It's aworked system. It's not really you
don't really need a very high level of
artificial intelligence for that. You
just need a powerful computer for that,
you know.
Uh so I don't think it's a proper AI
based defense system. It's just a
computerized defense system where the
computers they track the targets and
they direct the guns. They keep the guns
aimed on the on on individual targets
and fire at the right time. That is the
deal. The missile accuracy well the
missiles they have their own microchips
on board and they have radars that keep
on talking to the microchip. So it's
like a miniature computer on board the
missile. So as the missile is homing on
on the target, the tiger target will
take will take evasive action. Let's say
you're trying to take down take out an
aircraft fighter plane. Now the when you
launch a missile and the missiles radar
locks onto the target, the target will
also know that it's been painted by by
radar. So it's going to take action.
It's going to take evasive evas evasive
actions. It's going to deploy flares and
whatnot. And the missiles computer will
know what flares are like. So it will
ignore the flares and keep on looking at
the radar signature or the heat
signature of the target itself. So the
target maneuvers and the missile
maneuvers behind it. So that's not AI.
It's just the microchip and and the
logic built into it. So you see that's
the difference. So I'm not sure that we
have proper AI systems right now. In
case we do have them, I'll be very glad,
but I am a little skeptical at this
point.
Kapi developer says to be human is to be
skillful. The hope is to deploy these
talents for meaningful contribution,
making the world a better place for all.
Well, that's the hope of a good person.
If you are a good person, you want to
deploy your talents for a meaningful
contribution to make the world a better
place. But if you're not a good person,
you may deploy the talents for
non-meaning contribution or contribution
that's only meaningful for you, not for
others. And you may make the world worse
place. There are people like that too.
Um, so yeah, to be a productive human
being and a good human being, you you
should be skillful. If you are skillful,
you have something to offer to society,
something good to offer to society.
Yeah. So if you want to have a great
life, if you want to be someone
who feels happy with their contribution
in the world, then you have to be a
skillful person. You have to develop
skills. If you have no skills, you will
not have any sense of selfworth. You
will not be confident. You will feel
that you are not, you know, worthy of
various things and so on. So you have to
develop skills right and then you deploy
those skills talents for meaningful
meaningful contributions and make the
world a better place as much as possible
that well that's a fulfilling fulfilling
life in my opinion so I agree with you
sir Aries manticor says with the new
USPakistan deal terror camps will now
spread across Pakistan like poisonous
mushrooms with instead of a few potent
snakes it will be more decentralized and
more integrated with Pakistan civil
Pakistani civilians that's a possibility
that's a possibility ilityworked
terrorist camps, terrorist
infrastructure, decentralized terrorist
infrastructure.
It's it was already the case in Pakistan
because so many of the civilians have
terroristic tendencies. But uh yeah,
with if if the Pakistanis get
significant US protection, this could
proliferate more and it could become a
real problem for Pakistan as well as
India, for Pakistan as in the Pakistani
civilians and for Afghanistan as well,
maybe for Iran as well. So the sooner we
deal with Pakistan, the better it will
be for us. So your assessment seems to
be dangerously
correct. Yeah.
Yeah. If you if you have the blessing
and the protection of a major power like
the US, then you can and if you're a
terrorist nation, you can act with
impunity and you can you know do exactly
what you're saying. So yeah, that's
that's a real danger for us and for all
the neighbors that Pakistan has.
Kapay developer says why are Indian
companies not buying up GPUs? It's
because Indian companies are not those
companies that are not buying up GPUs
are the companies that are not
developing AI or not concerned about AI.
Right now let's say you are a
manufacturer of vehicles automoils.
In that case, you don't need to buy up
GPUs unless you want to uh develop
cuttingedge automobiles, futuristic
automobiles that will outperform
everything else in the world and you
want to to leverage AI to help you
design and develop those. In that case,
yeah, it makes sense. But Indian
companies are
they they use human designers who do
things on with with pencil on paper and
all that, right? So, yeah, it's India is
mired in the past. India doesn't have
any ambition. You have some people like
Shrider Wimbu of Zoho who is taking this
challenge head on. I'm glad to hear
this. There are other companies that are
taking the forefront in various other
domains right in in infrastructure
development not just in in India but
outside of India and those companies are
being targeted by by the US and and
actors within India they are being
maligned etc. And that's the case but
overall India doesn't seem to have taken
AI seriously at all. The US will develop
AI we will use their products that's it.
That's the kind of mindset the Indian
companies have. The Indian companies
don't have real leaders with any real
vision. The only vision is to make money
and and plate the shareholders. That's
all.
Rajendra Chula says, "You skipped two of
my questions. I asked four questions."
Well, if I see your questions, I'll take
them, sir. I'm taking all the super
chats one by one. All right, sir. Thank
you.
6P70 Delta says, "Please take my super
chat." Well, I just took your super
chat.
Am I skipping super chats? I think I'm
taking every single one one after the
other.
So, I'm not sure what has been skipped.
In case something has been skipped, I
apologize. I am taking all the questions
I'm seeing one by one. In case the
system or maybe the platform YouTube is
I don't know making not allowing me to
see some super chats, there's nothing I
can do about that. And for that I'll be
I apologize in in case some have been
skipped. All right gentlemen, ladies,
I'm taking all the super chats I can see
one by one by one.
Right. Okay. James says, "We were just
30 million and your people more than 1
billion. How did we colonize your
country? It just proves how weak and
fragile your country was up for sale.
Still is."
So
what James says is that the UK is 30
billion. We were more than 1 billion.
Look, when it comes to the past, when it
comes to the 16th, 17th, 18th centuries,
India's uh population was in the in the
vicinity of 300, 350 million.
And the UK, I'm not sure what the
population was, maybe 5 million or
something, whatever. The point is that
at the height at the height of the
British occupation of India,
there were about
20,000 British occupiers in India. If
you include the families and all that,
it will be close to a million British
people in India. But the actual
occupiers
which means that the army and military
officers and the uh civilian government
officials if you add those
[clears throat] up the British people
it's about 20,000 at the peak of the
British occupation of India. So 20,000
people men ruled over 350 million
Indians.
Right? What does it tell you?
It tells you that nonviolence
is such a lie. There are some
individuals who pedled nonviolence to
us. They said that we will defeat the
British through nonviolence. What you
did through nonviolence was delay our
independence by several decades and
allow the British to plunder India for
several decades more. That's what
nonviolence did. Let's say we had a
leader in 1915. Okay, let's say 1915.
And this leader gave a clarion call to
all Indians. Tomorrow morning go out of
your house, look for a British person.
When you see a British person, kill that
person.
You may die in the process. That's fine.
We have to sometimes die for our
motherland. Your job is to go out, seek
out a British person and kill that
person. Only one person you have to kill
and then go home. You your job is done.
And if Indians had done that by the end
of the day there would be not a single
British person left in India because we
are 350 million there are 20,000 at most
and India would be within 12 hours
independent.
Is it
unjust to kill your foreign occupiers
who are murdering your your your people
and plundering your country? Of course
it's not unjust. It's perfectly It's
perfectly legitimate to kill foreign
occupiers. Kill them all. Right?
So, it's because of leaders, fake
leaders who pretend pretended to be your
leaders but actually served the foreign
master that
20,000 British men were able to rule
over 350 million Indians
because of fake leaders and because of
the divisions that were swed in Indian
society. Right. So yeah, India was super
weak, super fragile and today it is even
weaker and more fragile because of the
divisions that have been swed in India
and the divisions are being widened
today. Lang linguistic divisions. My
language and your language, your
language is the language of enemies. My
language is better. My people are
better. Linguistic divisions, religious
divisions. The the today the the British
imposed cast system has been solidified.
Everything is based on cast,
reservations based on cast, votes based
on cast, everything cast. So cast
divisions now
right north, south, east, west
divisions,
all kinds of divisions, foreign
religions, Indian religions, Indian
religions. Within Indian religions, you
have other divisions that you want to
create. Veshava versus Shvite, uh maybe
Rajput versus X or Y or Zed. Everybody
wants to fight each other. And the
education system tells you that you all
you have to do to win is to issue words.
They will defeat you with words. My
slogan is greater than yours.
Indians don't understand what it means,
what it takes to to be powerful. They
don't understand the concept of power.
They don't understand the concept of
civilization. They don't understand the
concept of national interest. All thanks
to the education system. And why is the
education system not being changed if it
is so harmful? Maybe it serves some
people. So, I am grateful to James for
pointing these things out. I really
appreciate you, James. Thank you, sir.
Secret billionaire says what is actual
power? What with what kind of strings
can one control a nation or multiple
nations? Okay. Let's say you want to
control a city.
Forget about nation, right? Let's start
with the basics. Let's say you want to
control your neighborhood. Let's say
your neighborhood, let's say it's a
village, okay? Village of 1,000 people.
You want to control a village of 1,000
people and half the people are women.
obviously and then you will have maybe
20% children. So it leaves you with 300
males,
uh 200 kids and 500 women. That's the
village. How do you control them? All
you need is 20 thugs.
20 thugs who will terrorize the people
or who can potentially terrorize the
people. If you can control those 20
thugs, you can import them from
somewhere
and you give them some promises. We'll
give you power. We'll give you, you
know, we'll give you money. Whatever,
whatever it takes. You know, human
nature. If you understand human nature,
you can have 20 thugs at your disposal.
As as long as you have some money and
you can give them some benefits,
whatever benefits human nature seeks.
So with 20 thugs, you can control a
village of 20,000 especially who if
they're Indians because Indians are
nonviolent, right?
So with 20 thugs or maybe 30 thugs, you
can control a whole village of 1,000
people. Now let's say you have a town of
10,000 people. You may perhaps need 300
thugs,
maybe 500 thugs. I think 500 is
overkill. For Indians, 200, 300, 300 is
enough. So for a for a town of 10,000
people, you need 300 thugs, gundas,
hired gundas. For a city of a 100,000,
you may need 3,000 gundas. For a city of
million, you may need three need 3,000
gundas.
That's how it works. Real power comes
from the streets. If you can control the
streets, you can control everything. You
can control the votes.
You can control the votes if you can
control the streets. Do you understand?
So power is about control.
The more you can control, the more power
you have. Once you get the votes, you go
into you can you can control the laws.
You can control how the money is
distributed. You can control the budgets
[clears throat] and so much more. What
is actual power? The actual power is
your ability to unleash violence on
demand.
You may never use it, but you need to
have the ability to unleash violence on
demand in a calibrated fashion wherever
you want to apply it. That is actual
power.
That's the secret of power.
Power is not a uniform. Power is not a
seat somewhere.
Power is fear.
You won't fear somebody who is in a seat
but who actually doesn't have the
potential, the capability to unleash
violence on demand or to unleash mayhem
on demand or to ruin someone's life on
demand.
actual power is that
like Maetong said political power flows
out out of the barrel of a gun. So
that's power.
Ritik Vishnoi says when will Mr. Gandhi
and Mr. Nehu's true image be shown to
the people of India by the government of
India? Do you see anything coming like
this in the future? I see nothing like
that coming in the future.
No,
nothing not going to happen.
Sorry, I mean I don't have to apologize
but yeah
says since landing of Indian Globe
Master C7 on Bagram air base a few days
ago speculations are going on that the
Taliban has offered control of Bagram
air base to India. What is going on?
Wouldn't it infuriate the US and we will
have to face certain consequences?
So, a few days ago, like you rightfully
say,
an image emerged on social media of a
C17 Globe Master aircraft landing at
what looks like very much the Bagram Air
Base in Afghanistan, not very far from
the capital Kabul.
Now, the image that one sees, it is not
something that can be definitively
identified as an Indian aircraft.
And it's got some other editing on the
on the picture showing some some cartoon
like Pakistani general running away or
something. So that image has some edits
on it for sure. Uh let's let's I'm not
sure if I can find it. Anyway, uh the
point is
so it's it's not something that
can 100% be verified as an Indian
aircraft
because the the image has edits and
secondly you can't see Barati Vayena or
anything on the aircraft as far as I
saw. So I am not 100% convinced that
first of all this is an Indian C17 that
landed in Bram
now.
So that's number one. We're not sure.
Maybe it's an old image of an American
C7 that landed there because the
Americans controlled Bram, didn't they?
Right. And maybe the image has been
modified to to a certain extent and
edited
to make it look like maybe it's an
Indian one. Maybe. I don't know. But
assuming it's an Indian C7, maybe
there's a 10% probability that it's an
Indian C7 that actually landed there. So
assuming that probability is correct and
it's assuming that it's an Indian
aircraft that landed there,
what what does it mean? It could
potentially mean that India simply
landed an aircraft there to to to uh
deliver some supplies to Afghanistan
because we are sending supplies from
time to time to Afghanistan. We
typically send it through Chabahar port
or through some other route. Typically
through through Chabahar port in Iran
from which it is taken by road into
Afghanistan. But that takes a lot lot of
time. Maybe we needed to we needed to do
to deliver something a little faster and
that's why maybe we sent a C7 which is a
pretty large aircraft which can deliver
a lot of cargo. Maybe that's the case.
Um and maybe that's the one air base
that can take a plane of that size
because it's a pretty gigantic aircraft.
So that's another possibility. But what
if the Taliban has actually offered
control of Bagram to India? The question
is will Taliban will the Taliban do
that? See the Taliban are a PTO
nationalist government. They
are extremely
allergic to any kind of foreign presence
in their country.
They fought for decades to to evict the
Americans. Right? The Americans occupied
Afghanistan for 20 years and the Taliban
fought them consistently
and it was believed that the Taliban are
a Pakistani puppet. Well,
[snorts] that's not the case and I had
said this in 2021. The Taliban are not
going to be Pakistan's friends. They're
going to be India's friends. So, that
has exactly happened. Now, so
considering the fact that the Taliban
are push nationalists and they have
fought against foreign occupation of
their country, will they hand over
Bagram to India? They won't most likely
they will not most likely but they may
offer some kind of usage rights to
India. Maybe India will be given
permission to land aircraft there and
maybe park aircraft there for some time
as long as we don't take over the whole
air base. That may be possible. They may
allow Indian air traffic controllers to
to train Afghan air traffic controllers
and maybe to co-jintly operate or
whatever as long as the sovereignty and
authority lies in the hands of
Afghanistan.
So it may be a delicate kind of
situation, delicately positioned
situation where Afghanistan and the
Taliban actually control the air base
but it's kind of operated at least
partially by India and that sort of
thing may happen. So that is a
possibility that is definitely up there.
Now if that happens and if India starts
partially operating this air base with
the permission of the Taliban,
what happens with respect to the US?
Will it infuriate the US? It will very
much infuriate the US.
The Americans want the air base
themselves. They want complete control
of the air base all over again. The
Taliban won't allow that obviously and
that may
cause friction and it may have
consequences for the Taliban too. We'll
see about that. Uh
but if India starts partially operating
it, jointly operating it or whatever,
maybe the Americans will will will make
life difficult for India also in some
way or the other. Maybe you could have
Pakistani action of some kind, maybe
terrorist activity, maybe Pakistan tries
and hits the Bram air base.
You know, maybe Pakistani aircraft air
strikes may try to hit Pak the Bram air
base. Maybe Pakistan launches terrorist
attacks on India, maybe an Afghanistan.
So the Americans may weaponize Pakistan
if India starts operating background or
maybe something else. Maybe something
more direct, maybe sanctions, maybe more
tariffs, I don't know. So the Americans
have lots of options in their arsenal
when it comes to uh retaliating
against India and Afghanistan or
armwisting India. So if India does start
operating BAM to some extent, we should
expect trouble for sure.
Vitic Vishno is a new member. Thank you
so much sir. Thank you very much.
Vive Singh says how much role a
military-industrial complex can play in
our GDP. India can easily share their
missiles and ad export v varants to the
buyers.
Well, it depends on how GDP is
calculated or obviously if you have
major exports then your GDP rises. Uh so
if you have highquality weapons that the
world desires that the world seeks and
if you're able to export these in large
quantities in large volumes and that
brings in major major foreign exchange
into your country it can significantly
grow over GDP significantly. Right? So
yeah uh if if India becomes a major
missile exporter let's say we export
10,000 missiles a year okay let's say
that's a small number actually but let's
say we're exporting 10,000 a year and
each missile costs a million dollars so
that's 10 billion of revenue coming into
India which is not a big big deal
actually but let's say we are we are
bringing in a hundred billion dollars of
revenue that is what percentage of
India's GDP India's GDP is 4.5 trillion
And 10% is for what? What? 10% of that
is 450 million.
So it's like it's like half of that 5%
is about 225 million and
half of that so it's about 2% of India's
GDP grows if we have if you're exporting
a hundred billion of missiles only. But
let's say we are exporting $500 billion
various of worth of various things. It's
a 10% leaprog in our GDP, right? So that
sort of thing. So the
military-industrial complex, the more we
are able to export and sell to other
countries, the more our GDP grows
clearly. So as you can see, it's it's uh
it can have a major beneficial impact on
our GDP. Blur says, is in is the US
making way for other countries to get a
nuclear bomb? I was wondering when will
this question come?
It's almost two hours and this question
comes now. So the so Trump Mr. Trump the
US president uh recently put out a post
on social media saying that he has
greenlighted nuclear testing by the
United States
nuclear testing nuclear weapons tests.
So what does that really mean? He's
saying that other countries are testing
and the US has the world's largest
nuclear arsenal which is which is not
the case according to whatever the
western outlets are saying. Russia is
number one but he says America is number
one and he's saying that other countries
are testing apparently no one has tested
a nuclear weapon but he claimed that
that other countries have been testing
it testing nuclear weapons so he has
greenlighted American nuclear tests
apparently
so when it comes to Mr. Trump, we can't
really tell what is what is the truth,
what is hyperbol, what is fact, what is
not. You can't really take his his words
at face value. That's the kind of
president you have today. Half the
things he say makes no sense.
So, is he actually going to
have his military start conducting
nuclear tests all over again?
If that happens, I guarantee that Russia
will immediately start conducting
nuclear tests of its own. If that
happens, I would say India should not be
left behind. India should also test
various kinds of nuclear weapons,
whatever we need to test.
So um so the US may be paving the way
for other countries to start testing
nuclear weapons. If they test, other
countries will follow suit immediately.
Right? That that is that is almost a
guarantee. But are they paving the way
for other countries to get nuclear
bombs? I'm not sure about that. Not sure
about that. But nuclear tests looks like
that could be imminent if the Americans
go ahead with tests.
Vive Singh says Putin to visit India.
Put Putin visit to India in December.
India has reduced oil exports from
imports from Russia. How can we still
help Russia? Also US removed sanctions
from Javahar. What's happening? The US
has given a temporary extension on the
sanctions on Chabahar. I don't know 6
months or something. So it means that
every 6 months we have to go and beg the
Americans. Please please sir, please
give us another extension. That's
blackmail.
Okay, that's blackmail. They have not
given any any big favor. They have not
done any big favor to India. It's it's a
continuing blackmail. It means we can
keep we can keep on blackmailing you and
you to keep keep on coming and begging
us every 6 months. That sort of
situation. So it it automatically
signals to India that you are in an
inferior position and we are in in an in
a superior position.
Now when it comes to oil exports and all
it looks like India has somewhat
decreased our the imports that we are
oil imports from Russia. I'll have to
see about that. Is it because of an US
arm twisting? Is it because of oil
prices? I'm not sure. But it's
definitely
it's not like we have ended the oil
imports from Russia. We are still
importing oil from Russia but it looks
like there could be a decrease in the in
the volume of oil that we are importing
right. So we'll have to keep an eye on
that and if if this has really happened
and if there's a decrease significant
decrease then it's not well it's not the
greatest thing but Putin will visit
India in December and let's see what we
can do with that visit. That visit
should not be just handshakes and hugs
and nice talks and smiles and all that.
It should be substantive and and
something many things of actual
substance need to come out of it. A
visit is not for it's not for
socializing, right? It's for achieving
some objectives that cannot be achieved
at lower levels. So the two leaders of
the two countries should should take
things forward. So what would I expect
this visit to to produce? First of all,
the Sukoy 57 deal. I would like that to
happen, right? I would like India to
manufacture so 57s within India. Maybe
100, maybe 200 of those at least. Set up
a production line in a factory in India.
Not just assembling but manufacturing
those with [snorts] transfer of
technology. Then maybe the S500, maybe
some other things, maybe submarines,
maybe maybe ships, maybe maybe various
other kinds of weapon systems,
maybe talk about other issues. So I
would like to see substantive outcomes
coming out from the uh visit of of of
President Putin to India and that would
be great right so that would be mutually
see it's not like it's it's not about us
helping Russia whatever happens has to
be mutually beneficial it should help us
it should help them so if we start if we
agree to uh set up a Sukoy production
line or multiple production lines sukoy
57 production lines in India up with
transfer of technology it will not just
help India it will also help Russia
right because they will get the revenue
we will pay for that but we will produce
it over here so we get the aircraft they
get the money and it's it's a win-win
kind of thing we can even reexport it
back to Russia that sort of thing so
that's what I would like to see happen
says AI in biological weapons seems to
have been slept on by mainstream people
have forgotten COVID pandemic imagine a
newer more lethal virus AI design. Well,
I assure you it's happening behind the
scenes.
You see,
whenever there is a frightening epidemic
that emerges in Africa,
let's say for example, Ebola, you
sometimes have these outbreaks of Ebola
in certain parts of Africa. Quite rare,
but it happens once or twice a decade.
So, when there's an outbreak of Ebola in
Africa, what do you see happen? You see
a team of scientists rushing there from
the United States. You also see a team
of scientists coming in from China. They
go into this region of Africa, this part
of Africa where there is this most
frightful epidemic that's raging. They
go into that region, that very dangerous
region with the objective of helping the
people. Are they really helping the
people? What they're doing is they're
taking virus samples.
Why are they taking virus samples back
to their countries? to study them and
potentially weaponize them. Secrecy in
secrecy.
Right? So the US, the Chinese, they have
all kinds of viruses in their labs and
obviously they are studying the viruses
for various kinds of effect and maybe
secretly they are
you know editing those viruses because
viruses are essentially genetic ideas.
Viruses are somewhere on the dividing
line between alive and dead.
They're neither quite alive, they are
neither quite dead. Viruses, they they
have some of the properties that
crystals have, but they also have some
of the properties that living beings
have. One of the main properties is that
they have DNA. Some of them have RNA,
but they don't have full-fledged DNA.
They've got bits and pieces of DNA. They
are like genetic ideas. Some are good
ideas, some are terrible ideas. The
terrible ideas are very dangerous. So
you can take those ideas and take them
forward further further forward further
what whichever
right
and once you have AI you can
exponentiate that process yeah so
obviously this is something the media
won't report this is something that
happens behind utmost secrecy but it's
happening but it is indeed happening
Rajendra Chula says Russians see India
at par with Africa, Africans, dirty,
gross, etc. You say, you said we saved
Russia from China. Similar propaganda in
Central Asia. Who is doing this? Russia
ungrateful.
Look
at a government to government level. We
have the best relations. We have the
best strategic relations.
We have a significant element of trust
between India and Russia. When it comes
to the common person,
they see it they see us from the eyes of
whatever is reported in the media.
Maybe the Russian media also has been
guilty of of portraying India in a
certain way in the past. But are they
portraying India in an inaccurate manner
is what we have to ask ourselves. Is
India a super clean country? It's not.
It's not. Am I lying to you? Have you
been to India? Is India's infrastructure
fantastic?
If you're a tourist, do you is is your
experience fantastic when you come to
India?
If you're a tourist, you have to go
through immigration in India. Let's say
you've come on come in from a cruise
ship. Do you have any idea how much
trouble you're put through just to get
your passport examined and stamped? You
to stand in the sun. There's only one or
two passport officials for for a whole
shipload of passengers.
The other stalls are empty. Just one or
two bored looking passenger, you know,
officials. And you have to have your
luggage checked 23 times. Then you have
to deal with the traffic jam. You only
have 6 hours or 8 hours to see the city,
but 4 hours are gone just through the
process. And then then you are then you
get into the bus and you have a traffic
jam. And then you will see the cops ask
allegedly asking for bribes
for your driver or whatever. You will
see all kinds of terrible things. You
will see the garbage on the roads. You
will see the crumbling infrastructure.
You will see potholes.
If you see a river, you will smell the
river.
Are these issues that don't really ex
that don't exist in India? These are
real issues. So why are Indians getting
upset that these issues are being
reported by some people? Some people
prefer to see the good side of India.
Some people prefer to see the bad side
of India and some people see everything
there is.
And if you go to Russia, you will see
Russia is far better than India mostly.
So if Russians travel to India, they
will obviously not be happy with what
they see. So is is it Russia Russian
people being ungrateful? My point is we
have to be realistic. India is a third
world country with lots of problems and
people will report that some people will
like India and they will try to report
less of that but overall people will
report that and there are plenty of
these third rate westerners who come to
India only to visit slums and all that.
My point is why do slums exist?
Why do every why does every city
allegedly
have these slums?
Why
are these slums legal? When the slums
started, were they legal?
I mean, let's not even go into these
things, right? That's the point. Please
understand.
Rajendra Chula says EU, US getting
two-year visas for being BFGF.
If they get married, they get lifelong.
How does China protect their country
against spies?
EU, US getting two-year visas for being
boyfriend, girlfriend. If they get
married, they get lifelong
where in China or somewhere else?
I'm not sure exactly what you're asking.
Are they getting visas in the EU, in the
US, somewhere else?
And what is the relationship of of of
this of of of of this here with with
this?
How does China protect the country
against spies?
They
they uh keep an eye keep an eye on
everyone who enters the country. They
don't trust anyone. Everyone is spied
upon. Everyone is trailed. There's
electronic surveillance everywhere and
so much more. So the Chinese know how to
defend their country unlike India.
Arismantic horse says are we going to
witness a new age of overt nuclear
testing. Will we also see the rise of
Pakistan like US proxyinations with
nukes like Japan, South Korea, Saudis
etc.?
If the Americans go ahead with nuclear
testing then we will see other countries
immediately going forward with tests. If
the US conducts tests then immediately
the Russians will conduct tests and I
hope that we don't wait for 3 months
before we test
because India has been a very reactive
nation historically. I'm not saying
recently historically we have been a
super reactive nation. Our foreign
policy historically has been super
reactive. Nothing proactive about it. So
I hope that the if the Americans test
nuclear weapons, we will immediately on
the same day test nuclear weapons before
anybody can start warning others not to
test.
So if the Americans test, we will see
multiple nations potentially going ahead
and testing. Maybe the French will test
if they have if they still have
self-respect, right? The Russians will
definitely test. Maybe even the Chinese
will will test. So we should not get
left behind. Now will we see the see the
rise of Pakistan like US proximations of
nukes? Will Japan get nukes? Well, Henry
Kissinger said a year before he died,
few months before he died that within 5
years, Japan will be a nuclear powered
country, nuclear weapon country, nuclear
weapon power. So when did he die? Like 2
years ago. So maybe in 3 years, Japan,
if he's right, could have nuclear
weapons. South Korea, I don't know.
Saudis
uh
it's possible
if Kissinger was right, then Japan will
soon have nukes.
And Japan is kind of a shadow nuclear
power anyway. They have some of the best
technology in the world, right? Some
most of the technology is better than
what the US has. But the Japanese aren't
allowed to use the technology for their
own benefit because they are under US
occupation. But if the Americans give
them the go-ahhead, they will they can
develop nuclear weapons like next week.
So Japan is a shadow nuclear power. They
can have it soon. Uh South Korea will
need American help for that. Maybe,
maybe not. It may happen. Saudis only
have to pay some real to the Pakistanis
and they will have a few nuclear
weapons. So it could happen in the next
5 years potentially. AJ Sharma says
governments change, rules change. In the
end only my freedom and my own asset
matters. Is true personal sovereignty is
still possible today or no? It's not
possible.
Nope. Not possible. Why is it not
possible? You don't you don't really
control currency, do you? You use
currency that's issued by your
government or somebody else's
government. You have to abide by the
rules that they lay down. They can
punish you if you don't abide by the
rules. They can punish you if you break
the rules. They can punish you if you
fail to,
you know, uphold certain obligations.
Um,
in India, you don't even have the right
to personal property. It's not a it's
not a fundamental right. Um if you have
let's say property in the wrong part of
the city or the wrong part of whatever
and they want to construct a bypass
highway or whatever through it they're
going to demolish it. They will give you
some other property somewhere else as as
compensation but it may not be the same
quality location wise etc. So true
personal sovereignty is not possible
today. It's not the individual. As long
as you abide by all the rules and all
that, you will have a reasonably
independent life but not a sovereign
life. Right? So individual sovereignty
it's not possible today. It never has
been possible unless you were a hunter
gatherer or whatever. In that case you
were you had personal sovereignty but
you did have you did not have any of the
benefits of living in a society. That's
always a give and take kind of thing.
Kunal Krish says SpaceX mission to build
a moon base called Audacity. What are my
thoughts? I commend the vision of Elon
Musk. The man has a vision and he is
making it happen. Space B space space X
is in a position where they could launch
a Starship rocket to to the moon very
soon and the Starship rocket can carry I
don't know how many at least a 100 tons
of material into Earth orbit
and a few Starship launches is will
definitely be enough to set up a proper
moon base and he's going to call it
audacity. So I commend what Elon Musk is
doing and the US is so incredibly lucky
to have someone like him. And what are
my other thoughts? We are completely
left behind in the space race. India
India is no longer even a participant.
It looks like when was the how many
launches do we have every year? What are
we doing?
We have some of the best engineers and
scientists in this world. But what what
are what what use are they being put to?
What great challenge have been have they
been issued?
You have to issue people a great massive
challenge that is almost not achievable
humanly. That's when you get get the
best out of people and obviously you go
you've got to pay them well. What great
challenge does is has ISRO been given
today.
I don't know what sort of what our
leadership
is doing with ISRO. So anyway, good for
the US, good for the good for SpaceX.
They're going to lead the world in the
space race and they're going to lead the
world in the century it looks like and
India doesn't seem to have the
willingness to participate.
6P70 Delta says your opinion on MIG31
and its face off with NATO Italian F-35s
in Estonia airspace and US purchase of
old Mig 31s from Kazakhstan. I am not
aware of this incident that you are
referring to. Uh Mig 31 face off with
F-35s, NATO F35s, Italian F-35s in
Estonian airspace.
So if this sort of faceoff happened in
Estonian airspace, let's look at the map
so that we understand what we are
dealing with. Where is Estonia? It's a
Baltic nation. All right, let's go and
zoom in very quickly instead of taking
you slowly through it. This is Estonia.
It's a nation that used to be part of
the USSR. It's just west of St.
Petersburg, you know, and if there was
an incident where Russian Mig 31
faced off with F-35s from NATO. Well,
that's interesting. It means Russia is
pushing the boundaries now and it's
issuing warnings to other countries,
countries that are aligned with the West
that uh yeah, it's it's warning
essentially. It's a warning. Now, I'm
not sure what was the outcome of uh this
face off because I'm not aware of it.
And US purchase of old big 31 from
Kazakhstan. Well, it's a smart move. If
I was the US, I would also purchase
Russian weaponry, weaponry that Russia
is currently using from wherever it's
available. So that you understand the
machine very well. So what you do is you
purchase a MIG 31 from let's say
Kazakhstan, which will make Putin very
unhappy with Kazakhstan first of all,
but that's a different story. You
purchase the machine, then you put your
engineers and test pilots to work. you
your engineers first of all underscore
understand the entire functioning of the
of the machine and then you have your
test pilots take it for a spin. So once
your test pilots get get the hang of how
to fly this thing, then you have dog
fights and whatnot with your with your
F-35s or other aircraft with your test
pilot flying the big 31 so that your
fighters, your your your pilots know
exactly how to deal with this thing.
Makes a lot of sense.
Literally officer cases. Why is
secularism so successful compared to
religious governments? A classic case is
Malaysia versus secular Singapore or
secular Turkey versus Pakistan.
Secularism is mainly a slogan
unless it is in India where it is very
literally hindophobia.
So let's take Malaysia versus Singapore.
Singapore
is a secular nation. Sure. And it is way
more successful than Malaysia. Why is it
way more successful? Singapore is also
historically way more successful than
China.
China is not secular but it's an
atheistic country which is well kind of
like secularism right? So Singapore is
successful because it's a city state.
It's tiny. You want to turn something
around the smaller it is the faster it
turns right? So Singapore
and Malaysia, you can't really compare.
Malaysia is much larger, but Malaysia is
now today on the verge of becoming a
first world nation. That is success.
Turkey versus Pakistan. It has nothing
to do with secularism. Turkey is an
Islamic country even if they are
technically secular.
Pakistan is a third rate country that is
run by a mercenary government which is
nothing but the Pakistani military.
That's why Pakistan is not successful.
It has nothing to do with secularism.
So this is the propaganda that is fed to
us that so and so thing is is success is
is is responsible for success when it's
it's a whole different set of factors.
Pakistan is a failure because it is a
dictatorship. It's a military
dictatorship. The military doesn't care
about their people their their country.
They are willing to sell the country off
peace by piece.
And that's why Pakistan is a disaster
and because they have adopted terrorism
as a state policy. That's why Pakistan
is a disaster. Turkey hasn't done those
things. It has nothing to do with
secularism. Malaysia, Singapore,
Malaysia, the size difference is the is
the reason for the difference. But
Malaysia still is now on the verge of
becoming a first world country. So that
is success. So please understand it's
nothing to do with secularism.
YAT says Israel launched a new
communication satellite today. Really?
Really? Israel launched something today?
Well, I'm so glad. How is it significant
geopolitically? I have no idea. I have
not aware of this launch. How can India
now give live updates, maps to armed
forces during a conflict conflict? No, I
don't know what the satellite is about.
I have not seen the news. See, I am not
a news surfer. I am not a journalist.
I am the last person who can be called a
journalist. A journalist and a news
surfer and a news reader is a person who
will keep on watching the news and who
will report the news live to you as it
happens. I don't do that.
I don't look at what happened today or
yesterday. I look at things from from a
macro perspective. What happened in the
last week, what happened in the last
month? I analyze that. I don't care
about what's happening right now. Latest
update. I don't care about the latest
updates. If it's important, I'll know
about it eventually. So, I don't know
what this new satellite is. If it's a
communication satellite, what manner of
communication satellite is it?
We could quickly take a look at uh the
news headlines.
What's it say? Okay, let's go to Google.
ISRO
launch. Let's see what's it. Heaviest
communication satellite CMS03.
Bahubali rocket. Well, let's not give
this weird slogans. Baloo Bahubali
rocket. It's a medium launch rocket at
best. But anyway,
so LVM3 M5 launch, ISRO shoots off
India's heaviest communic communication
satellite on the largest on the most
powerful rocket that we have.
Uh spectacular display etc. heavyweight
rocket.
Uh the heaviest satellite is 4,400 kg.
Okay. It's in a geostrynchronous
transfer orbit. Uh all of that that's
fine. Fantastic. What is the
but what does the satellite do? Please
let us know that too. LBM3 blah blah
blah blah blah blah pertinent etc. CMS03
multiband communication satellite. It
will provide services over a wide
oceanic region including the Indian land
mass services to whom?
Okay. Gat 7R is it the CMS03 is it Gat
Gat 7R? Maybe it's two names of the same
thing. advanced most advanced
communication satellite. It's developed
for the Indian Navy. Indigenously
designed and developed uh etc. New
generation of state-of-the-art
components. Operational needs of Navy.
Uh multiband transponders that support
high speed voice data video
communication links. Secure and
uninterrupted connectivity between the
Navy submarines, ships, aircraft and
maritime communication centers. It will
play a p pivotal role in integrating
India's expanding network of maritime
surveillance and communication assets.
All of that all weather conditions
mission critical communication
subsurface surface aerial platforms
force multiply all that stuff. Okay.
Realtime awareness.
Okay. So it's a naval satellite. It's a
satellite that is that is intended for
helping the navy communicate. It will
allow the Navy to see the battle space
in a more integrated fashion. It'll
allow the various assets of the navy to
to communicate with with each other in
real time. So if you have a submarine,
if you go if you got a a frig, if you
have a destroyer, if you have something
else, aircraft carrier, and all of these
ships, they all have their own sense of
what's happening, and you can all upload
all of that to the satellite. It'll give
each of these assets an integrated
picture of the battle space. It'll allow
all of them to communicate with each
other in real time, video, data, etc.,
and that sort of thing. It's good. It's
a good good uh step forward, right? So,
it is significant geopolitically because
it it gives more teeth to the Indian
Navy, right? Good. Glad to see this. And
I'm glad to see this large rocket taking
off successfully and launching a
satellite and placing it into orbit.
Good.
Rick Rywick says, "Please recommend top
books for learning the history of
Manipur in depth. I have no idea.
I I don't know any see if you want to
study the history of Manipur there are
various books written by the British one
is Grimwood
Estel Grimwood or whatever okay that's a
British view of Manipur um Manipur
Grimwood
Ethel Grimwood yeah okay her husband was
the political
officer political agent in IAL and he
was killed by Manipuri freedom fighters
Okay. Three years in Manipur and escape
from whatever escape from the recent
mutiny by Ethel St. Clare Grimwood. So
that's that's a book about Manipur
written from the perspective of a
British woman whose husband was a
political agent who was killed by the
Manipuri freedom fighters. Uh there is
that. What else? The another one is the
Chaitar Kumbaba.
Um one second
Chaitar
Kumbaba. I'm not sure if it's in print
anymore. This is the royal chronicle of
the kings of Manipur.
And it gives you the history of the
kings of Manipur of the past 2,000
years.
All right. 2,000 years of Manipuri of
the history of Manipuri kings. It may be
available on the internet archive. Let's
see if the full text is available or
only a partial text. Maybe the full text
is available. I'm not sure about the
quality of the text and so on. Yeah,
it's in it's in Manipuri but in the
Bengali script it's not a translation
into English. Okay. So that's going to
be an issue for most of us. Is it
available on Amazon? It is currently
unavailable. So if you can get your
hands on this, it can be really useful.
Uh apart from that I am not really sure.
There are all kinds of recent histories
written by god knows what people
including people who are not manipuris
but claim to be manipuris. In that case
it's it's going to be super distorted
history of Manipur. So I can recommend
these two books. One is a pretty
completely Anglocentric perspective
written by that lady Grimwood
and the other one is the Chhataral
Kumbaba the the Chronicle of the Kings
but it doesn't seem to be in print.
That's the issue anyhow. And please
continue the book recommendations in
your study 8 hours live streams as
you've done previously. Well, I'm no
longer doing those 8 hour live streams,
right? So, how do I continue the book
recommendations? What I can do is I can
make clips of those book recommendation
segments and upload them to the channel.
I'm sure it'll be
perhaps useful to
many of you. Uh, apart from that, I'll
see maybe in the future I could perhaps
do more book recommendation videos
separately. I'll see. Okay. Sid says,
"How can how India how can India win an
AI war when necessary hardware is
controlled by the US? India may have
software talent, but hardwares like
GPUs, it's still owned by the West."
Well, you see, we will have to develop
all this capability ourselves.
There's no other option.
We have to develop all of this
ourselves. We need to manufacture the
hardware ourselves. We need to set up
semiconductor manufacturing in India. uh
chip manufacturing in India. We need to
start making all these chips our on our
own. It'll take us 10 20 years otherwise
we will be completely dependent on
outsiders and they can cut off the
supply whenever they feel like. There is
no other option. We are late. We have
been sleeping.
We could have been one of the pioneers
of AI of chief development. If the uh if
those fac that factory that was that was
in operation in the what 1980s 1990s it
was not destroyed burned down
mysteriously and never revived. So our
own people do these things to us right?
So anyway we have been sleeping we are
we are perennially reactive and that's
why we are currently so far behind
right now. There's no way that India can
in the near future win any AI war. But
in the next 20 years, let's see. We
could perhaps be a be somewhere in the
race. Maybe in the next 10 years if we
get things right.
Right. Okay. I suppose that's about it
for the super charts. We are almost at
two and a half hours.
Uh IM artistic says we reached 8
nanometers in 6 months from 21
nanometers in chips. So that is
significant progress.
significant progress and that is very
encouraging to see. So let's let's hope
we keep on making very rapid progress
and uh let's be positive about it. Let's
be optimistic
and maybe then in a few years maybe two
three years we'll be somewhere somewhere
you know in in in the race. So I hope it
does happen that way. I hope it does
right. Let's not be all doom and gloom
and negative. Let's be positive. Let's
be optimistic.
Okay, gentlemen and ladies, thank you
very much. Ritik P says, "My two super
chats missing." Well, you see my dear
friend Ritwick and whoever else who have
faced this issue, I have taken every
single super chat that is visible to me.
So, in case some super chats were
swallowed by YouTube, I am sorry about
that. But there's nothing I can do about
it, right? I apologize. But I have taken
every single one. I was supposed to end
this live stream bit in two hours but I
always take it I always extend it until
I answer all the super chats. So sorry
about that and uh hopefully next time
this doesn't happen. Hopefully next time
YouTube is more cooperative. Okay. All
right. Let's let's end this here. Thank
you so much. Next weekend I am going to
be traveling. I'm going to be in Jaipur.
So next weekend I will not be able to do
the ask Abhabijit live streams. Would
you like me to do a live stream on
Wednesday
which is way before the weekend? If
that's something you would like, I'll be
happy to do it. Let me know in the
comments below and I look forward to
seeing you in the next live stream.
Maybe I will take questions and maybe I
will put out an Ask a Ask a Widget
episode that is recorded but it still
takes your questions. a spade. Yes,
Japur dialogues. So, okay, I will do a
live stream on Wednesday then. Okay, one
day before I leave. I look forward to
seeing you there. Thank you so much
everybody. Thank you for everything.
Thank you for your viewership, for your
questions. Keep learning. Mary Kane,
thank you very much. Mahita Bushi, thank
you so much. Yes, Jaipur dialogues. Yes,
I I'm going to be there. In case any of
you are going to be in Jaipur, I will be
very pleased to meet you there. All
right. Uh so, let me know. Take care
everyone. Thank you so much and I look
forward to seeing you in the next one.
Keep learning, keep asking questions,
keep raising your standards. Thank you.